<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
     xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
     xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
        >

    <channel>
        <title>American Go E-Journal</title>
        <atom:link href="http://www.usgo.org/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <link>http://www.usgo.org/news</link>
        <description>Updated World Go News</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 11:56:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
        <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
        <generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4.1</generator>
        <item>
            <title>Andy Liu 1P Sweeps YKNOT3</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/new-american-pro-andy-liu-sweeps-yknot3/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/new-american-pro-andy-liu-sweeps-yknot3/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 00:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Chris Garlock</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Main Page]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184473</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[In the exciting concluding rounds to the third annual Young Kwon National Online Tournament, new American professional Andy Liu became this year&#8217;s champion, winning all five rounds. Liu earned professional status at last year&#8217;s
download SGF file
first AGA professional&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the exciting concluding rounds to the third annual Young Kwon National Online Tournament, new American professional Andy Liu became this year&#8217;s champion, winning all five rounds. Liu earned professional status at last year&#8217;s</p>
<p><a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.17_YKNOT_ALiu-YZhang_Rd5.sgf">download SGF file</a></p>
<p>first AGA professional qualification event, sponsored by TygemGO, which took place just prior to the US Go Congress in North Carolina. Liqun Liu 7D took second in the 2013 YKNOT, winning 4 out of 5. Other band winners include Aaron Ye 5D, Willis Huang 3D, Larry Qu 1K, Matthew Machado 5K, and Yuliang Huang 21K. The tournament took place over the first two weekends in June on KGS. There were a total of about 60 players, some of whom were new AGA members, and for others, this was their very first online tournament. YKNOT3 sponsor Young Kwon was on hand during the rounds to watch the games and comment. TD Karoline Burrall extended thanks to all of the players who participated in the tournament. &#8220;Thanks also to our fantastic sponsor Young Kwon,&#8221; added Burrall, &#8220;as well as the team of TDs including Dennis Wheeler, Todd Heidenreich, Jay Tabaniag, and Julie Burrall.&#8221;</p>
<p>Andy Liu&#8217;s 5th-round game against Yue Zhang 7D &#8212; &#8220;Full of fighting and lively viewer commentary!&#8221; &#8212; is at right.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/new-american-pro-andy-liu-sweeps-yknot3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Wilson Zhang Wins Happy Cup</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/zhang-wins-happy-cup/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/zhang-wins-happy-cup/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 00:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Paul Barchilon</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Main Page]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Youth]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184487</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Seventh-grader Wilson Zhang 1k topped the Sixth Sunflower Happy Cup Youth Go Tournament, with four wins, on June 1 in Cupertino, California. “Forty-one elementary and middle school kids gathered together on a beautiful Saturday afternoon and played four to five&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/zhang-wins-happy-cup/attachment/01/" rel="attachment wp-att-184488"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-184488" style="margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" title="01" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/01.jpg" alt="" width="360" height="239" /></a>Seventh-grader Wilson Zhang 1k topped the Sixth Sunflower Happy Cup Youth Go Tournament, with four wins, on June 1 in Cupertino, California. “Forty-one elementary and middle school kids gathered together on a beautiful Saturday afternoon and played four to five rounds of 19×19 games,” reports Wenguang Wang, who organized the event. &#8220;To ensure a really fun experience for every kid, players earned prize tickets after each round, and then exchanged their tickets for various fancy prizes. Each participant was also rewarded with a trophy, and at the event’s conclusion all the kids and their parents enjoyed a refreshing ice cream party.” <em>-Paul Barchilon, E-J Youth Editor. Photo by Ming Liao. Wilson Zhang is at left, in the blue shirt</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/zhang-wins-happy-cup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Local Organizers Oppose Nihon Kiin Plan to Sell New York Go Center</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/local-organizers-oppose-nihon-kiin-plan-to-sell-new-york-go-center/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/local-organizers-oppose-nihon-kiin-plan-to-sell-new-york-go-center/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 21:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Roy Laird</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Main Page]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184455</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[The Nihon Kiin has informed Nihon Kiin America (NKA) that it intends to sell the East 52nd St building that formerly housed the New York Go Center. Nihon Ki-in CEO Mr. Hanyu will be in New York this week to discuss&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nihonkiin.or.jp/index-e.htm">The Nihon Kiin</a> has informed Nihon Kiin America (NKA) that it intends to sell the East 52nd St building that formerly housed <a href="https://www.facebook.com/NYGoCenter">the New York Go Center.</a> Nihon<a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.17_NYGCandyliulesson.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-184477" title="2013.06.17_NYGCandyliulesson" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.17_NYGCandyliulesson-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a> Ki-in CEO Mr. Hanyu will be in New York this week to discuss the matter further with Terry Benson, NKA President.  &#8220;We think it&#8217;s a mistake to sell,&#8221; Benson says,  &#8221;especially with New York real estate values climbing. We presented them with a detailed plan by which the building could be put back in use, pay for the cost to do so in less than three years, and be a permanent source of funds to cover its expenses and produce money to benefit American go. The plan was never given serious consideration.&#8221;</p>
<p>In a conference call Mr. Hanyu told NKA board members that the proceeds would be used to benefit American go. However Mr. Hanyu also said that the American community would only be &#8220;consulted&#8221; in determining how the funds would be used. The Nihon Ki-in would have the final authority. He also would not say whether the building would be offered for competitive bids in a public sale or in a private transaction like the one the Nihon Ki-in tried to close in 2011.  &#8220;The Nihon Kiin has a fiduciary responsibility to make the most of Iwamoto sensei&#8217;s gift. A private sale to a friendly buyer would raise obvious suspicions. We will insist on transparency in everything to do with the building,&#8221; says Benson. &#8220;Iwamoto&#8217;s endowment to US go must benefit and be controlled by those who know how to promote go in the US. We hope the Nihon Ki-in honors Iwamoto&#8217;s intentions.&#8221;<br />
<em>- photo: Andy Liu giving a lesson at the NYGC; photo by Roy Laird</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/local-organizers-oppose-nihon-kiin-plan-to-sell-new-york-go-center/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Power Report: China Dominates 18th LG Cup; Catching Up On &#8220;Go Go Japan&#8221;; 4th Asian Indoor &amp; Martial Arts Games to Include Go</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/the-power-report-china-dominates-18th-lg-cup-catching-up-on-go-go-japan-4th-asian-indoor-martial-arts-games-to-include-go/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/the-power-report-china-dominates-18th-lg-cup-catching-up-on-go-go-japan-4th-asian-indoor-martial-arts-games-to-include-go/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Chris Garlock</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Main Page]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[World]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184480</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[by John Power, Japan Correspondent for the American Go E-Journal
<strong>China Dominates 18th LG Cup:&#8230;</strong> The opening rounds of this Korean-sponsored international tournament were held in the city of Kangnung (also written Gangneung) in Korea on June 10 &#38; 12.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>by John Power, Japan Correspondent for the American Go E-Journal</em></p>
<p><strong>China Dominates 18th LG Cup:</strong> The opening rounds of this Korean-sponsored international tournament were held in the city of Kangnung (also written Gangneung) in Korea on June 10 &amp; 12. An excellent report has already been presented <em>(<a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/korea-knocked-out-in-lg-cup-stunner-japan-fights-on/">Korea Knocked Out In LG Cup Stunner; Japan Fights On</a> 6/13)</em>, so this report will fill in some some details.<a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.17_China-LG-Team.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-184483" title="2013.06.17_China-LG-Team" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.17_China-LG-Team.jpg" alt="" width="330" height="220" /></a></p>
<p>The main news is undoubtedly the great success of the new young generation of Chinese players, who took six of the quarterfinal places. However, Japan also made a good start: with just four seeded players taking part (it failed to win any seats in the qualifying tournament), it secured two quarterfinal places, its best result for some years. Also, although he was eliminated in the 2nd round, Kono Rin 9P scored an excellent win in the first round, beating the player who recently won the Ing Cup, Fan Tingyu 9P of China.</p>
<p>The interesting point about the Chinese success is that the main contribution<br />
is not being made by its senior players, such as Gu Li 9P, but by players in their teens and early 20s (I include ages below for the Chinese players to demonstrate this). It really does seem that by your late 20s you are past your peak in China and also in international go. This is also borne out by the early elimination of such great Korean players as the two Yis, Ch’ang-ho and Se-tol, Pak Yeong-hun, Pak Cheong-hwan, and others; these are names to conjure with, but they don’t overawe the Chinese youngsters. Japan operates by different rules, of course; apart from Iyama, its top players are in their thirties.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.17_quarter-finalists-18th-LG-Cup-550x368.jpg"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-184484" style="margin: 5px;" title="2013.06.17_quarter-finalists-18th-LG-Cup-550x368" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.17_quarter-finalists-18th-LG-Cup-550x368.jpg" alt="" width="440" height="294" /></a>Full results for the opening rounds:<br />
Round One (June 10): Kono Rin 9P (Japan) (B) defeated Fan Tingyu 9P (aged 16) (China) by resignation; Iyama Yuta 9P (Japan) (W) d. Zhang Tao 3-dan (aged 21) (China) by resig; Takao Shinji 9P (Japan) (B) d. Hong Seong-chi 9P (Korea) by resig; Mok Chin-seok 9P (Korea) (B) d. Hane Naoki 9P (Japan) by half a point; Kim Seong-chin 2P (Korea) (W) d. Gu Li 9P (aged 30) (China) by resig; Li Zhe 6P (aged 23) (China) (B) d. Kang Tong-yun 9P (Korea) by resig; Zhou Ruiyang 9P (aged 22) (China) (B) d. Ch’oe Ch’eol-han 9P (Korea) by resig; Yi Se-tol 9P (Korea) (B) d. Xie Erhao 1P (aged 14) (China) by resig; Li Qincheng 2P (aged 14) (China) (W) d. Pak Yeong-hun 9P (Korea) by resig; Guo Yuzhang 3P (aged 20) (China) (B) d. Cho Han-seung 9P (Korea) by resig; Xia Chenkun 2P (aged 20) (China) (W) d. Kim Chi-seok 9P (Korea) by half a point; Tuo Jiaxi 3P (aged 22) (China) (B) d. Yi Ch’ang-ho 9P (Korea) by resig; Yi Yeong-ku 9P (Korea) (W) d. Xiao Zhenghao 8P (Chinese Taipei) by resig; An Hyeong-chun 4P (Korea) (W) d. Shi Yue 5P (aged 22; winner of the 17th LG Cup) (China) by 5.5 points; An Cho-yeong 9P (Korea) (W) d. Han Yizhou 2P (aged 16) (China) by resig; Chen Yaoye 9P (aged 23) (China) (W) d. Pak Cheong-hwan 9P (Korea) by resig.</p>
<p>Round 2 (June 12): Takao (B) d. Guo by resig; Iyama (W) d Yi Yeong-ku by 1.5 points; Chen (B) d. Kono by resig; Li Qincheng (W) d. Mok by resig; Li Zhe (B) d. An Hyeong-chun by resig; Tuo (B) d. Yi Se-tol by resig; Zhou (B) d. An Cho-yeong by 2.5 points; Xia (W) d. Kim by 2.5 points.</p>
<p>Quarterfinal pairings (November 11): Iyama vs. Chen, Takao vs. Tuo, Zhou vs. Li Qincheng, Li Zhe vs. Xia.<br />
<em>photos: (top right): Team China (from left): <a title="Yu Bin" href="http://gogameguru.com/tag/yu-bin/">Yu Bin</a>, <a title="Li Zhe" href="http://gogameguru.com/tag/li-zhe/">Li Zhe</a>, <a title="Zhou Ruiyang" href="http://gogameguru.com/tag/zhou-ruiyang/">Zhou Ruiyang</a> and Xia Chenkun; (bottom left): 18th LG Cup quarter finalists (from left): Chen Yaoye, Iyama Yuta, Tuo Jiaxi, Takao Shinji, Li Zhe, Xia Chenkun, Li Qincheng and Zhou Ruiyang. Photos courtesy <a href="http://gogameguru.com">Go Game Guru</a></em></p>
<p><strong>Catching Up On &#8220;Go Go Japan&#8221;:</strong> Two places out of eight may not seem a spectacular success, but for Japan it’s a big improvement on recent results. The go media here has been giving much of the credit to the foundation of a national team. Since I omitted to report on this earlier, now is a good time to catch up. Go Go Japan, the name of the national team, was chosen in a poll of go fans and announced on May 20 (the first word is English and the second refers to the game). The actual founding of a national team by the Nihon Ki-in and the Kansai Ki-in is dated to April 1 this year; the aim is to promote solidarity in international competition and to improve results. Members are the top 15 players in the prize-winning list, players with previous good results in international tournaments, the winners of the King of the New Stars, Hiroshima Aluminium Cup, the Okage Cup and Nakano Cup, the top ten women players, and all teenaged players, with the last-mentioned given the status of trainees (all of the above must volunteer for the team, though). This is quite a large pool, but there’s some overlap and the membership for the opening year, including coaches and playing coaches, amounts to 32 players. In theory, training camps and other events may be held, but the main activity so far has been setting aside Fridays and Saturdays for senior members of the team to play training games on the Net with the junior players. The most famous of the 30 players on the team are Iyama Yuta, Yamashita Keigo, Hane Naoki, Cho U, Takao Shinji, Kono Rin, Yuki Satoshi, and O Meien. Coaches are Yamashiro Hiroshi, who is also Vice President of the Board of Directors of the Nihon Ki-in, and Cho Riyu 8-dan, with Cho U and Takao acting as playing coaches. It’s hard to know how much of a boost the formation of the national team gave to the players competing in the LG Cup, but it’s certainly the focal point of the news coverage in Japan. Local fans are certainly hoping that this opening success is not a flash in the pan.<a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.17_AsianGamesIncheon.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-184492" title="2013.06.17_AsianGamesIncheon" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.17_AsianGamesIncheon.jpg" alt="" width="224" height="114" /></a></p>
<p><strong>4th Asian Indoor &amp; Martial Arts Games to Include Go</strong>: The 4th Asian Indoor &amp; Martial Arts Games will be held in Incheon City in Korea from June 30 to July 5. Eight sports will be featured, including go, chess, billiards, bowling, and kick boxing. Participation represents yet another advance in raising the profile of go as a sport in Asia, following the major breakthrough in having it included as a regular competition sport at the 16th Asian Games in 2010. The Asian Indoor and Martial Arts Games are organized by the Olympic Committee of Asia and are held every four years in the year before the Asian Games. They are staged at the same venue, and Incheon will host this event and the 17th Asian Games next year. There are three go events: male individual, Pair Go (referred to as Rapid Mixed Team on the event’s HP), and male team. Ten countries or territories are taking part: Korea, China, Japan, Chinese Taipei, Malaysia, Singapore, Mongolia, Vietnam, Chinese Hong Kong, and Macao. Countries with professional organizations are fielding teams of low-dan, young players. The players representing Japan will be Hirata Tomoya 3P (aged 19), Tsuruta Kazushi 2P (aged 18), Motoki Katsuya 2P (aged 17), Sada Atsushi 1P (aged 17), Okuda Aya 3P (aged 24) and Fujisawa Rina 1P (aged 14).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/the-power-report-china-dominates-18th-lg-cup-catching-up-on-go-go-japan-4th-asian-indoor-martial-arts-games-to-include-go/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>This Week&#8217;s Go Calendar: Arlington, Evanston, Rio Rancho, Sacramento, Lancaster, St. Paul</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/this-weeks-go-calendar-arlington-evanston-rio-rancho-sacramento-lancaster-st-paul/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/this-weeks-go-calendar-arlington-evanston-rio-rancho-sacramento-lancaster-st-paul/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 12:46:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Roger Schrag</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Calendar]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Main Page]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184462</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<strong>June 22: Arlington, VA</strong>
NOVA School&#8217;s Out
Gary Smith gary@novagoclub.org 703-254-6429
<strong>June 22: Evanston, IL</strong>
Here Comes The Sun
Mark Rubenstein mark@evanstongoclub.org 847-869-6020
<strong>June 22: Rio Rancho, NM&#8230;</strong>
New Mexico Summer Go Tournament
Robert Cordingley rjcord1@gmail.com 505-471-4569
Daniel Dawes djdoz19@gmail.com]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>June 22: Arlington, VA</strong><br />
<a href="http://www.novagoclub.org/tournaments">NOVA School&#8217;s Out</a><br />
Gary Smith <a href="mailto:gary@novagoclub.org">gary@novagoclub.org</a> 703-254-6429</p>
<p><strong>June 22: Evanston, IL</strong><br />
<a href="http://www.evanstongoclub.org">Here Comes The Sun</a><br />
Mark Rubenstein <a href="mailto:mark@evanstongoclub.org">mark@evanstongoclub.org</a> 847-869-6020</p>
<p><strong>June 22: Rio Rancho, NM</strong><br />
<a href="http://www.goclubs.org/dbm/Tlogin.php">New Mexico Summer Go Tournament</a><br />
Robert Cordingley <a href="mailto:rjcord1@gmail.com">rjcord1@gmail.com</a> 505-471-4569<br />
Daniel Dawes <a href="mailto:djdoz19@gmail.com">djdoz19@gmail.com</a> 505-261-4159</p>
<p><strong>June 22: Sacramento, CA</strong><br />
Davis/Sacramento Summer Quarterly<br />
Willard Haynes <a href="mailto:willard@emeritus.csus.edu">willard@emeritus.csus.edu</a> 916-929-6112</p>
<p><strong>June 23: Lancaster, PA</strong><br />
<a href="http://harrisburgareagoclub.org/tournament.php">Lancaster Summer Ratings Tournament</a><br />
Jason Long <a href="mailto:jason@long.name">jason@long.name</a> 717-315-9097<br />
Sam Zimmerman <a href="mailto:szimmerman@ctipc.com">szimmerman@ctipc.com</a></p>
<p><strong>June 23: St. Paul, MN</strong><br />
2013 TCGO Summer Tournament<br />
Aaron Broege <a href="mailto:broe0034@umn.edu">broe0034@umn.edu</a> 612-384-8789</p>
<p>Get the latest <a href="http://www.usgo.org/event-calendar">go events information</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/this-weeks-go-calendar-arlington-evanston-rio-rancho-sacramento-lancaster-st-paul/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Google Donates $120,000 in Free Ads to AGF</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/google-donates-120000-in-free-ads-to-agf/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/google-donates-120000-in-free-ads-to-agf/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 04:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Roy Laird</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Youth]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184092</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Google has agreed to donate up to $120,000 per year to the American Go Foundation (AGF) in free AdWords, those text-based ads you see to the right when you search on Google. The AGF received this benefit by qualifying as&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Google has agreed to donate up to $120,000 per year to the <a href="http://agfgo.org/pages/home.php">American Go </a><a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.03_GoogleAdwords.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-184152" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.03_GoogleAdwords.jpg" alt="" width="348" height="145" /></a><a href="http://agfgo.org/pages/home.php">Foundation</a> (AGF) in free AdWords, those text-based ads you see to the right when you search on Google. The AGF received this benefit by qualifying as a <a href="http://www.google.com/nonprofits/" target="_blank">Google Nonprofit</a>, a status available to 501c3 corporations. “This is a great new way to reach out to players, teachers, librarians, organizers and people who ought to be players,” said AGF President Terry Benson. The AGF&#8217;s first AdWords campaign attracted almost 200 hits in the first week, with a &#8220;Got Best Game?&#8221; theme; traffic on the AGF website is up at least 30%. Another benefit of the program is access to <a href="http://www.google.com/onetoday/" target="_blank">One Today</a>, a crowdsourced microfinance fundraising app for 501c3s. The app, currently only available for Android, presents users with one charity every day, and asks for a donation of one dollar, or more if a donor is so inclined.  Multiple charities are displayed each day, and users can pick who they want to donate to. The AGF is working on a One Today profile, and will go live on the app in the near future.  Like Microsoft, Exxon, and other major corporations, Google also matches the contributions of employees who make charitable donations to organizations like the AGF. <em>-Roy Laird</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/google-donates-120000-in-free-ads-to-agf/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>New AGA Pro To Play in First Korean Tournament</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/new-aga-pro-to-play-in-first-korean-tournament/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/new-aga-pro-to-play-in-first-korean-tournament/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 22:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Paul Barchilon</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[World]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Youth]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184416</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Gansheng Shi 1p, who qualified with Andy Liu 1p as an AGA pro in last year&#8217;s certification tournament, is scheduled to play in his first Korean pro tournament, the KT-Olleh Cup, on Monday June 17th.  The young Canadian will play&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/new-aga-pro-to-play-in-first-korean-tournament/screen-shot-2013-06-13-at-4-41-59-pm/" rel="attachment wp-att-184430"><img class="alignright  wp-image-184430" style="margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" title="Screen shot 2013-06-13 at 4.41.59 PM" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Screen-shot-2013-06-13-at-4.41.59-PM-600x427.png" alt="" width="360" height="256" /></a>Gansheng Shi 1p, who qualified with Andy Liu 1p as an AGA pro in last year&#8217;s certification tournament, is scheduled to play in his first Korean pro tournament, the KT-Olleh Cup, on Monday June 17th.  The young Canadian will play alongside Korean professionals and even receive a small game fee for playing.  Top prize in the tournament is $100,000.  The KT-Olleh is one of five tournaments that the Hankuk Kiwon (KBA) agreed to allow newly certified AGA pros to play in, and the first to start since Shi traveled to Korea last month. The next scheduled of the five is the Samsung Cup in August.  &#8220;My goal in tournaments would be to win at least one game but it seems very difficult,&#8221; Shi told the EJ.  Shi is studying at the Choong-Am Dojang in Seoul, with travel support from the AGA and tuition support from the KBA.</p>
<p>Shi says he is enjoying Korea, Korean food, and some new friends. He describes the Choong-Am as a &#8220;really quiet nice place to focus on go,&#8221; although he had difficulty adjusting at first. &#8220;I started off in league C &#8230; The first 2-3 weeks were really bad and I had a horrible losing record of something like 3-9, then I managed to stabilize in the league and was able to stay in league C without being moved to league D.  The new month just started and I have been doing great so far, winning most of my games and I really hope to move to the next league after this month.&#8221;  Shi fills his days with self-study of pro games and life and death until lunch, a game and then review with a teacher in the afternoon, more self-study and some exercise, and then a game after dinner. &#8220;I do feel like I&#8217;m progressing, because I have been improving in my record and winning a lot of games lately. Perhaps that is just me stabilizing but I do feel that I am learning a lot in the dojang.&#8221;  <em>-Andy Okun.  Photo: Shi playing a simul at the Spring Go Expo earlier this year, from The Surrounding Game&#8217;s <a href="https://www.facebook.com/SurroundingGameMovie" target="_blank">Facebook Page</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/new-aga-pro-to-play-in-first-korean-tournament/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Takemiya Confirmed for U.S. Go Congress; Chinese Weiqi Names Two from Chongqing Go Team</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/takemiya-confirmed-for-u-s-go-congress-chinese-weiqi-names-two-from-chongqing-go-team/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/takemiya-confirmed-for-u-s-go-congress-chinese-weiqi-names-two-from-chongqing-go-team/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 22:42:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Chris Garlock</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S. Go Congress]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184398</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[The Nihon Ki-in has just confirmed that the legendary Takemiya Masaki 9P will attend the 2013 U.S. Go Congress, which runs August 3-11 in Tacoma, WA. Famous for his &#8216;cosmic style&#8216; of play &#8211; focusing on the construction of large moyos&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Nihon Ki-in has just confirmed that the legendary <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?TakemiyaMasaki">Takemiya Masaki 9P</a> will<a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.13_Takemiya-Masaki-and-Ing-final-game.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-184426" title="2013.06.13_Takemiya Masaki and Ing final game" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.13_Takemiya-Masaki-and-Ing-final-game.jpg" alt="" width="228" height="300" /></a> attend the <a href="http://www.gocongress.org/">2013 U.S. Go Congress</a>, which runs August 3-11 in Tacoma, WA. Famous <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.18_Yang-Yi.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-184515" title="2013.06.18_Yang Yi" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.18_Yang-Yi-104x150.jpg" alt="" width="104" height="150" /></a>for his &#8216;<a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?CosmicStyle">cosmic style</a>&#8216; of play &#8211; focusing on the construction of large <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?Moyo">moyo</a>s and taking territory in the center &#8212; Takemiya wowed 2009 Congress attendees with his lectures, game commentaries and demonstrations of ballroom dancing. “We are so thrilled to welcome Takemiya sensei back to the U.S. Go Congress,” said American Go Association President Andy Okun. “We’re sure he’ll be even more illuminating and entertaining this year.” The Chinese Weiqi Association has also just announced that they’re sending two attendees – Yang Yi 6P and Chen Wei 3P &#8212; to the Go Congress. Yang <em>(top left)</em> is director of the Chongqing Qiyuan and senior coach of the Chongqing Go Team, while Chen <em>(bottom left)</em>, <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.18_Chen-Wei.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-184516" title="2013.06.18_Chen Wei" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.18_Chen-Wei-103x150.jpg" alt="" width="103" height="150" /></a>also from the Chongqing Qiyuan, is Coach of the Chongqing Go Team. Chen primarily teaches now, and more than forty of his students have achieved amateur 5-Dan status. &#8220;We are deeply grateful to Chinese Weiqi for the help and collegiality in spreading go and building the go community in North America,&#8221; said Okun.<br />
<em>- includes reporting by Lee Anne Bowie; Takemiya photo by Phil Straus</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/takemiya-confirmed-for-u-s-go-congress-chinese-weiqi-names-two-from-chongqing-go-team/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Korea Knocked Out In LG Cup Stunner; Japan Fights On</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/korea-knocked-out-in-lg-cup-stunner-japan-fights-on/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/korea-knocked-out-in-lg-cup-stunner-japan-fights-on/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 22:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Annalia Linnan</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Events/Tournaments]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Go News]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Go World]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184374</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[For the first time in the history of the LG Cup, there are no Koreans in the quarter final line-up. Korean fans were left in shock after Tuo Jiaxi 3P (left) knocked out Lee Sedol 9P (right) in a game with a very&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For the first time in the history of the LG Cup, there are no Koreans in the quarter final line-up. Korean fans were left in shock after <a title="Tuo Jiaxi" href="http://gogameguru.com/tag/tuo-jiaxi/">Tuo Jiaxi</a> 3P <em>(left)</em> knocked <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.13_Tuo-Jiaxi-Lee-Sedol-18th-LG-Cup-300x199.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-184411" title="2013.06.13_Tuo-Jiaxi-Lee-Sedol-18th-LG-Cup-300x199" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.13_Tuo-Jiaxi-Lee-Sedol-18th-LG-Cup-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" /></a>out <a title="Lee Sedol" href="http://gogameguru.com/tag/lee-sedol/">Lee Sedol</a> 9P<em> (right)</em> in a game with a very unusual opening. Japan <a title="Japan strikes back! The 18th LG Cup" href="http://gogameguru.com/japan-strikes-back-18th-lg-cup/">continued the charge</a> through the draw, with two of the Japanese players, <a title="Iyama Yuta" href="http://gogameguru.com/tag/iyama-yuta/">Iyama Yuta</a> 9P and <a title="Takao Shinji" href="http://gogameguru.com/tag/takao-shinji/">Takao Shinji</a> 9P, making it through, while <a title="Kono Rin" href="http://gogameguru.com/tag/kono-rin/">Kono Rin</a> 9P was defeated by <a title="Chen Yaoye" href="http://gogameguru.com/top-20-go-players-cho-hanseung-chen-yaoye/">Chen Yaoye</a> 9P. This is the first time Japanese players have made it through to the quarter finals of the LG Cup since 2008, when Kono Rin did so. If Iyama or Takao manages to win the 18th LG Cup, it will be Japan’s first victory in this tournament since O Rissei (who was born in Taiwan) won it in <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.13_Kono-Rin-Takao-Shinji-Yamashiro-Hiroshi-Iyama-Yuta-Hane-Naoki-18th-LG-Cup-550x368.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-184413" style="margin: 5px;" title="2013.06.13_Kono-Rin-Takao-Shinji-Yamashiro-Hiroshi-Iyama-Yuta-Hane-Naoki-18th-LG-Cup-550x368" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.13_Kono-Rin-Takao-Shinji-Yamashiro-Hiroshi-Iyama-Yuta-Hane-Naoki-18th-LG-Cup-550x368-150x100.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="100" /></a>1998. There are six Chinese players still in the draw. The most notable is <a title="Li Zhe" href="http://gogameguru.com/top-20-go-players-won-seongjin-li-zhe/">Li Zhe</a> 6P, who is making an amazing comeback from his sabbatical, storming his way to the quarter final. Chen, Tuo and Li will be joined by their countrymen, <a title="Zhou Ruiyang" href="http://gogameguru.com/top-20-go-players-zhou-ruiyang-tuo-jiaxi/">Zhou Ruiyang</a> 9P, <a title="Li Qincheng" href="http://gogameguru.com/tag/li-qincheng/">Li Qincheng</a> 1P and <a title="Xia Chenkun" href="http://gogameguru.com/tag/xia-chenkun/">Xia Chenkun</a> 2P. The two youngsters, Xia Chenkun and Li Qincheng, could turn out to be the dark horses in this competition, as China has some frighteningly strong children coming through the ranks. Though the quarter finals and semifinals will not take place until November, Japanese finalists Iyama and Takao will duel it out in the fourth game of the Honinbo on June 17 and 18. Meanwhile, Chinese finalist Chen Yaoye will compete against defending champion Lee Sedol on the international front at the Chunlan Cup also on June 17.<br />
<em>-Annalia Linnan, based on reports &#8212; including pairings, photos, and game records &#8212; on <a href="http://gogameguru.com/">Go Game Guru</a>. photo at bottom left: Team Japan (from left, clockwise): Kono Rin, Takao Shinji, Yamashiro Hiroshi, Iyama Yuta and Hane Naoki. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/korea-knocked-out-in-lg-cup-stunner-japan-fights-on/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>UK Pair Go Monarchs Lose Crowns But Still Best-Dressed</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/uk-pair-go-monarchs-lose-crowns-but-still-best-dressed/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/uk-pair-go-monarchs-lose-crowns-but-still-best-dressed/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 22:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Tony Collman</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Go News]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184305</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[England&#8217;s reigning pair go King and Queen lost their crowns last weekend. At the June 9 British Pair Go Championships, 25-time British Champion Matthew MacFadyen 6d and his wife and pair go partner Kirsty Healey 2k won the final game by 12.5 points to usurp&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>England&#8217;s reigning pair go King and Queen lost their crowns last weekend. At <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.13_Cocke_Regan.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-184420" title="2013.06.13_Cocke_Regan" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.13_Cocke_Regan-300x223.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="223" /></a>the June 9 <a href="http://britgo.org/tournaments/pairgo">British Pair Go Championships</a>, 25-time British Champion <a href="http://www.europeangodatabase.eu/EGD/Player_Card.php?&amp;key=10249019">Matthew MacFadyen</a> 6d and his wife and pair go partner <a href="http://www.europeangodatabase.eu/EGD/Player_Card.php?&amp;key=10698809">Kirsty Healey</a> 2k won the final game by 12.5 points to usurp the UK pair go throne held by 2012 champs <a href="http://www.europeangodatabase.eu/EGD/Player_Card.php?key=10262021">Matthew Cocke</a> 5d and <a href="http://www.europeangodatabase.eu/EGD/Player_Card.php?&amp;key=12301146">Natasha Regan</a> 1k <em>.</em> The outgoing royalty took some consolation from their prize for Best-Dressed pair, having come attired as a medieval royal couple <em>(photo)</em>.</p>
<p>Eight pairs competed in the main tournament, for which <a href="http://britgo.org/reps/wpairgo.html">world amateur pair go</a> and <a href="http://britgo.org/reps/epairgo.html">European pair go</a> qualification points were allocated. A further seven pairs played in a separate handicap tournament, won by <a href="http://www.europeangodatabase.eu/EGD/Player_Card.php?&amp;key=16433032">Rebecca Margetts</a> 20k and <a href="http://www.europeangodatabase.eu/EGD/Player_Card.php?&amp;key=14701874">Oscar Selby</a> 9k.</p>
<p>The event took place at Foxcombe Lodge Hotel, Boars Hill, near Oxford, England, and was organised by Francis Roads on behalf of the British Go Association (BGA). Click here for <a href="http://britgo.org/results/2013/rengo">full results</a>.<br />
<em>- Tony Collman, based on material on the <a href="http://britgo.org/">BGA&#8217;s website</a>; photo by Tony Atkins<br />
CORRECTION (6/17):  MacFadyen-Healey won the final game by 12.5 points, not 2.5 as originally reported. </em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/uk-pair-go-monarchs-lose-crowns-but-still-best-dressed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A Google Doodle for Go Seigen?</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/a-google-doodle-for-go-seigen/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/a-google-doodle-for-go-seigen/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 22:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Chris Garlock</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[World]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184368</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[On Go Seigen&#8217;s 99th birthday, Go Game Guru renewed the call for a Google Doodle next year on the go master&#8217;s 100th birthday.
Google regularly changes the logo on their homepage to mark the anniversary of important events and celebrate the achievements&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On Go Seigen&#8217;s 99th birthday, <a href="http://gogameguru.com/">Go Game Guru</a> renewed the call for a Google Doodle next year on the go master&#8217;s<a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.12_Go-Seigen-6th-Ing-Cup.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-184369" style="margin: 5px;" title="2013.06.12_Go-Seigen-6th-Ing-Cup" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.12_Go-Seigen-6th-Ing-Cup-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a> 100th birthday.</p>
<p>Google <a href="http://www.google.com/doodles/">regularly changes the logo</a> on their homepage to mark the anniversary of important events and celebrate the achievements of great scientists and artists. These are called <a href="http://www.google.com/doodles/about">Google Doodles</a>.</p>
<p>“Since Go Seigen will turn 100 in 2014, we thought it would be great if we, as a community of go players, could convince Google to celebrate Go Seigen’s 100th birthday with us,” said Go Game Guru&#8217;s David Ormerod. “Not only would this be a great way to mark the world’s greatest go player becoming a centenarian, it would also introduce many new people to this fascinating game.”</p>
<p>Email <a href="proposals@google.com" rel="nofollow">proposals@google.com</a> and ask them to celebrate Go Seigen’s 100th birthday on June 12, 2014. <a href="http://gogameguru.com/go-seigen/">Click here</a> for Go Game Guru&#8217;s report, which includes an overview of the life of the “living legend.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/a-google-doodle-for-go-seigen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Go Helps Minority Cultures Preserve Their Traditions in U.S.</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/go-helps-minority-cultures-preserve-their-traditions-in-u-s/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/go-helps-minority-cultures-preserve-their-traditions-in-u-s/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 14:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Roy Laird</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Youth]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184097</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[How can minority cultures gain acceptance in American society without abandoning their cultural values and traditions? The game of go may be one way.
One Friday last month, Academy of the Americas (AoA) students traveled to Kalamazoo, Michigan with the Go Cultural Ambassador&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>How can minority cultures gain acceptance in American society without abandoning their cultural values and traditions? The game of go may be one way.</p>
<p>One Friday last month, <a href="http://detroitk12.org/schools/school/341/" target="_blank">Academy of the Americas</a> (AoA) students traveled to Kalamazoo, Michigan with the Go Cultural Ambassador International Program (GCAIP) where Detroit and Ypsilanti youth taught Kalamazoo students how to play go. They related the ancient board game to community building, anti-<a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.07_Uriel-AOA-GCA-teaching-El-Sol-Go.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-184253" title="2013.06.07_Uriel AOA GCA teaching El Sol Go" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.07_Uriel-AOA-GCA-teaching-El-Sol-Go.jpg" alt="" width="432" height="257" /></a>bullying and peer mentorship in the kindergarten through higher education continuum, influenced by the anti-bullying work of top pro Yasutoshi Yasuda.</p>
<p>GCAIP’s mission is to promote global citizenship and cultural validation with an emphasis on academic excellence in the social sciences and humanities. It uses go to bridge and even transcend cultural differences. Eighty students aged 9-13 attended the daylong event at the Western Michigan University College of Health and Human Services.  Participants analyzed the first <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hikaru_no_Go" target="_blank">Hikaru No Go</a> anime with faculty assistance using the theories of “cultural humility” and “transformative complicity.” The young students “grasped college-level theory leaving Diana Hernandez, WMU’s Director of the Division of Multicultural Affairs,  in shock,” according to WMU Assistant Professor  <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ogR30KnwSKo&amp;list=PLwOvGooFAolsQimicoPFM-hFAenGtPQ35&amp;index=17" target="_blank">Dr. Roxanna Duntley-Matos</a> who is also the co-founder of the Asociacion Latina Alcanzando Suenos (ALAS) and GCAIP.</p>
<p>Detroit youth paired up with El Sol Elementary teachers and students and with University of Michigan faculty Dr. Robert M. Ortega (known for his promotion of cultural humility in child welfare) to discuss how their game strategies reflected their personalities (i.e. risk taker, adventurous, aggressive or cautious).   WMU provided university flags and patches to inspire participants to work hard and return in a few years as college students. Live music and a karate demonstration led by Martin Gatlin added to the festival-like atmosphere. “The day ended with students dancing the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bachata_%28dance%29" target="_blank">bachata</a> and <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ogR30KnwSKo&amp;list=PLwOvGooFAolsQimicoPFM-hFAenGtPQ35&amp;index=17" target="_blank">merengue</a> giving the entire day a true Latino touch,” Matos said. “All in all, we had people from two universities, three schools and one community program blending elements from Latino, African American, Euro-American and Asian cultures.”</p>
<p>GCAIP has other activities in the works.  It plans to visit groups in Grand Rapids and Wayne State University and hopes to connect with a new program in Puerto Rico. They already have ongoing relationships with programs in Oregon and Mexico. “Go is more than a game of strategy, it is a way of life. It connects people and communities together,” says Oscar Hernandez, one Detroit youth GO Cultural Ambassador;</p>
<p>GCAIP, AoA and ALAS credit Dr. Earlie Washington, Dean of WMU CHHS and Dr. Linwood Cousins, Director of  the WMU School of Social Work for providing invaluable institutional support. They also thank Kelly Alvarez, Terry Gay, Anne Bowman, Jinny Zeigler, Ernestina Iglesias and Jennifer Clements for helping to organize the Kalamazoo event celebrating AoA’s 20th anniversary and honoring GCAIP co-founder and recently deceased AoA Principal Mrs. Denise Fielder. AoA’s GCAIP Director Mark Duffy played a crucial role continuing the instructional work of Siddhartha Avila, GCAIP co-founder from Pipiolo Elementary School in Mexico. Special thanks from ALAS to Portland organizer Peter Freedman and karate instructor Martin Gatlin for weekly go training over the Internet for the past year.<br />
<em>- Roy Laird; photo: El Sol students learn go; photo by Diana Hernandez</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/go-helps-minority-cultures-preserve-their-traditions-in-u-s/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>EuroGoTV Updates: Ireland, Romania &amp; Hungary</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/eurogotv-updates-ireland-romania-hungary/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/eurogotv-updates-ireland-romania-hungary/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 14:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Annalia Linnan</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Events/Tournaments]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Go News]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184330</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<strong>Ireland:</strong> At the Galway Go Tournament, Justyna Klezcar 2k (right) bested Thomas Shanahan 6k while Anthony Durity 7k placed third. <strong>Romania:&#8230;</strong> In Braila, Theodor Toma 2d conquered the under-18 Campionatul National de Go knock-out. Behind Toma were Elian Ioan Grigoriu]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright" src="http://eurogotv.com/maaktagjpg.php?fotoid=http://lh6.ggpht.com/-cxJraLqVqSw/UGv3UltQajI/AAAAAAABl4Y/tRS3jAfAB3Q/IMG_3863.JPG&amp;links=16&amp;rechts=79&amp;boven=18&amp;onder=70&amp;titel=Justyna%20%20Kleczar%202k&amp;pin=13886169" alt="galway go tournament" width="208" height="186" /><strong>Ireland:</strong> At the Galway Go Tournament, Justyna Klezcar 2k (<em>right</em>) bested Thomas Shanahan 6k while Anthony Durity 7k placed third. <strong>Romania:</strong> In Braila, Theodor Toma 2d conquered the under-18 Campionatul National de Go knock-out. Behind Toma were Elian Ioan Grigoriu 2k and Alexandru Georgian Iacob 2k. <strong>Hungary:</strong> Renato Tolgyesi 1k defeated Dominik Boviz 3d at the 3rd Csiki Cup Group 5 tournament in Budapest; Robert Czismadia 3k took third.<br />
<em>-Annalia Linnan, based on reports on <a href="http://eurogotv.com/">EuroGoTV</a>, where complete result tables and all the latest European go news are available.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/eurogotv-updates-ireland-romania-hungary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Go Camp Updates: Video Posted; One More Camper Needed</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/go-camp-video-need-just-one-more-camper/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/go-camp-video-need-just-one-more-camper/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 23:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Paul Barchilon</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Youth]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184322</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[AGA Go Camp Director Amanda Miller is gearing up for this year’s camp, and has nine students enrolled so far.  ”We need just one more student to break even, so if you have been thinking about camp, now is the&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>AGA Go Camp Director Amanda Miller is gearing up for this year’s camp, and <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Screen-shot-2013-06-11-at-5.19.36-PM.png"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-184323" style="margin: 5px;" title="Screen shot 2013-06-11 at 5.19.36 PM" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Screen-shot-2013-06-11-at-5.19.36-PM-300x214.png" alt="" width="300" height="214" /></a>has nine students enrolled so far.  ”We need just one more student to break even, so if you have been thinking about camp, now is the time to sign up!” Miller says.</p>
<p>Camp will be held July 20-27 at YMCA Camp T. Frank Soles in Rockwood, Pennsylvania. A <a href="http://youtu.be/a01AlTFskxc">promotional video</a> from a previous camp captures the exciting camp experience on film. Check out camp information, pictures and news on the camp’s <a href="http://www.gocampeast.org/">website</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://agfgo.org/pages/scholarships.php#summerscholarship">AGF Scholarships</a> are still available to help defray the cost for kids who need it. AGA President Andy Okun has confirmed the camp will run this year, even if it’s at a small loss, “but breaking even would be much better.”<br />
<em>-Paul Barchilon, E-J Youth Editor.</em><em> </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/go-camp-video-need-just-one-more-camper/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>DC &amp; Toronto Lead Pandanet-AGA City Leagues; Round 8 Set for Sunday</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/dc-toronto-round-8-set-for-sunday/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/dc-toronto-round-8-set-for-sunday/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:44:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Chris Garlock</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184299</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Greater Washington has a slim one-point edge over Los Angeles in the the Pandanet-AGA City A League after seven rounds of play. In the B League Toronto has come out with a strong record and is leading the league with San Francisco&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: small;">Greater Washington has a slim one-point edge over Los Angeles in the the <a href="http://pandanet-igs.com/communities/agacityleague">Pandanet-AGA City A League</a> after seven rounds of play. In the B League Toronto has come out with a strong record and is leading the league with San Francisco hot on their heels. Round 8 is set for this Sunday, June 16 at 2p on IGS. In the A League, Los Angeles will play New York City, Greater Washington will play Boston, and Seattle will play Vancouver. With the field so strong at this point, Boston could wind up challenging LA and GW for the top slot. In the B League, Southern California will take on San Francisco in a tough match-up, Massachusetts will play Washington DC&#8217;s Team 2 and Toronto will play Montreal. It will be exciting to see if Toronto will gain another win to stay on top of the standings or will there be a tight playoff the last two rounds to determine the winner. Up-to-date standings are available on the <a href="http://pandanet-igs.com/communities/agacityleague">Pandanet-AGA City League Page</a>. </span></span></span></p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: small;">While t<span style="color: #222222;">he east coast has arguably been dominating national tournaments in recent years, LA found a secret weapon in 22-year-old anchor B</span><span style="color: #4c4c4c;">eomGeun ‘Evan’ Cho 7D. The former Korean insei is 6-0 in the league, and has defeated several former US Open and/or North American Masters champs including Jie Li 7D, Andy Liu 1P, Ziyang Hu 1P and Huiren Yang 1P. And with </span><span style="color: #222222;">Daniel Ko and Curtis Tang on tap, the LA team is so solid that if a team cannot beat Cho, then it must beat both Ko and Tang. Team captain Andrew Okun, President of the American Go Association, probably knows how to motivate his team. Meanwhile, with AGA legend Jie Li on board, DC is a legitimate champion candidate. Vancouver&#8217;s 2-4 score may be a bit of a surprise, but if they get Ziyang Hu 1P back to the lineup, they are still in the striking range. Boston is 3-0 against three teams with 2 wins, yet win-less against top two teams; it may be time for the team to step out of their “comfort zone”. Seattle has demonstrated the powerful strength of Korean American players, while New York City is also strong, but just has not yet had a good opening. Toronto is leading after beating San Francisco but the DC Team 2 is closely behind, followed by Montreal, Southern CA and Massachusetts.</span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: small;">Jon Boley and Steve Colburn head up the team running the City League, in which teams from North American cities play in a league system on the Pandanet-IGS server in the AGA room. The teams consist of up to five players, out of which three are selected to play in each round.<br />
</span></span></span><em><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: small;">- report by Steve Colburn and Edward Zhang</span></span></span></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/dc-toronto-round-8-set-for-sunday/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Go Classified: Goban For Sale</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/go-classified-goban-for-sale-2/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/go-classified-goban-for-sale-2/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Chris Garlock</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Go Classified]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184296</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Katsura goban, 4.5 inches thick.  With legs, total height 9.5 inches.  20 years old, but only used by a little old man on Sundays. Bob Barber; komoku@clear.net&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Katsura goban, 4.5 inches thick.  With legs, total height 9.5 inches.  20 years old, but only used by a little old man on Sundays. Bob Barber; <a href="mailto:komoku@clear.net">komoku@clear.net</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/go-classified-goban-for-sale-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>This Week&#8217;s Go Calendar: Portland, Santa Monica, Tempe, Mountain View</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/this-weeks-go-calendar-portland-santa-monica-tempe-mountain-view/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/this-weeks-go-calendar-portland-santa-monica-tempe-mountain-view/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 13:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Roger Schrag</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Calendar]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184216</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<strong>June 15: Portland, OR</strong>
Guo Juan Pro Workshop
Peter Freedman peter.freedman@comcast.net 503-242-4203
<strong>June 15, Santa Monica, CA</strong>
7th Annual Santa Monica Coffee Cup
Andrew Okun bcd@okun.name 310-346-5850
<strong>June 15 and 18: Tempe, AZ&#8230;</strong>
AZ June Rating Tournament
Bill Gundberg bill@azgoclub.org]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>June 15: Portland, OR</strong><br />
Guo Juan Pro Workshop<br />
Peter Freedman <a href="mailto:peter.freedman@comcast.net">peter.freedman@comcast.net</a> 503-242-4203</p>
<p><strong>June 15, Santa Monica, CA</strong><br />
<a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/170118573155101/">7th Annual Santa Monica Coffee Cup</a><br />
Andrew Okun <a href="mailto:bcd@okun.name">bcd@okun.name</a> 310-346-5850</p>
<p><strong>June 15 and 18: Tempe, AZ</strong><br />
AZ June Rating Tournament<br />
Bill Gundberg <a href="mailto:bill@azgoclub.org">bill@azgoclub.org</a> 480-831-5567</p>
<p><strong>June 17-21: Mountain View, CA</strong><br />
<a href="http://jiangmingjiu.blogspot.com/">2013 Summer Go Day Camp</a><br />
Mingjiu Jiang <a href="mailto:mingjiu7p@hotmail.com">mingjiu7p@hotmail.com</a> 650-796-1602</p>
<p>Get the latest <a href="http://www.usgo.org/event-calendar">go events information</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/this-weeks-go-calendar-portland-santa-monica-tempe-mountain-view/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Nominations For 2013 AGA Board Directors Closing June 15</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/nominations-for-2013-aga-board-directors-closing-june-15/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/nominations-for-2013-aga-board-directors-closing-june-15/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 21:18:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Chris Garlock</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184276</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[The central region American Go Association board seat remains wide open as no names have been submitted as candidates, reports Arnold Eudell. “Incumbents Paul Celmer and Chris Kirschner remain the sole candidates in the eastern and western regions respectively.” Eudell&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>The central region American Go Association board seat remains wide open as no names have been submitted as candidates, reports Arnold Eudell. “Incumbents Paul Celmer and Chris Kirschner remain the sole candidates in the eastern and western regions respectively.” Eudell added. Nominations close Saturday, June 15 </span></span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>and must be sent to </span></span></span><a href="mailto:elections@usgo.org"><span style="color: #1155cc;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>elections@usgo.org</span></span></span></a><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">. Click here for <a href="http://www.usgo.org/aga-board-elections">procedures, qualifications and candidate statements</a></span></span><span style="color: #1155cc;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>. </span></span></span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/nominations-for-2013-aga-board-directors-closing-june-15/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Power Report: Cho U Wins Crucial Game In Meijin League; Takao Takes Lead In Honinbo Title Match; Kono To Challenge Iyama For Gosei Title; New Professional Couple</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/the-power-report-cho-u-wins-crucial-game-in-meijin-league-takao-takes-lead-in-honinbo-title-match-kono-to-challenge-iyama-for-gosei-title-new-professional-couple/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/the-power-report-cho-u-wins-crucial-game-in-meijin-league-takao-takes-lead-in-honinbo-title-match-kono-to-challenge-iyama-for-gosei-title-new-professional-couple/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 19:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Chris Garlock</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[World]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184261</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[by John Power,  Japan Correspondent for the American Go E-Journal<strong style="color: #222222;">
Cho U Wins Crucial Game In Meijin League:&#8230;</strong> Thanks to defeating his most formidable opponent, Cho U 9P (right) is a lot closer to ecoming the challenger for the 38th Meijin]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><em>by John Power, </em><em> Japan Correspondent for the American Go E-Journal</em><strong style="color: #222222;"></p>
<p>Cho U Wins Crucial Game In Meijin League:</strong><span style="color: #222222;"> Thanks to defeating his most formidable opponent, Cho U 9P <em>(right)</em> is a lot closer to <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.09_ChoU.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-184262" title="2013.06.09_ChoU" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.09_ChoU.jpg" alt="" width="154" height="142" /></a>ecoming the challenger for the 38th Meijin title. In a game played on June 1, Cho (taking black) defeated Iyama Yuta Honinbo by resignation, improving his record to 6-0 and keeping the sole lead. Iyama had been one of just two players with only one loss, but, with his score now 5-2, the best he can hope for is a tie for first, but that will happen only if Cho loses both his remaining games; his opponents are Takao Shinji 9P and Kono Rin 9P. The other player with one loss is Hane Naoki 9P, who is on 4-1; he has already played Cho, so he has to rely on the above-mentioned pair for help in catching up. Incidentally, Saturday games are quite unusual, but Iyama is extremely busy,</span><span style="color: #1155cc; font-size: medium;"> </span></span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>what with Honinbo games in successive weeks. On June 6, Sakai Hideyuki 8P (B) defeated Yuki Satoshi Judan by resignation. This was Sakai’s first win in the league, to six losses, while Yuki still has not opened his account. He is now 0-6 and has suffered a dismal 16 losses in a row, spread over three Meijin leagues.</span></span></span></p>
<p><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span><strong>Takao Takes Lead In Honinbo Title Match:</strong> All the momentum now seems to be with Takao Shinji 9P <em>(left)</em> in the 68th Honinbo title <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.09_TakaoShinji9P.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-184263" style="margin: 5px;" title="2013.06.09_TakaoShinji9P" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.09_TakaoShinji9P.jpg" alt="" width="170" height="210" /></a>match. In the third game, played in the Hokkaido city of Kushiro on June 5 &amp; 6, he defeated the defending champion Iyama Yuta and took a 2-1 lead. Playing black, Takao forced a resignation after 167 moves. In its report, Go Weekly was unable to specify a losing move for Iyama; he apparently played no dubious moves after the opening, so Takao must have gained an advantage in the first fight of the game, in which he sacrificed corner stones to set up a squeeze on the outside. Iyama has now lost three important games on the trot; the fourth Honinbo game, scheduled for June 17 &amp; 18, will be a crucial one for his title defense.</span></span></span></p>
<p><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span><strong>Kono To Challenge Iyama For Gosei Title:</strong> In the final of the 38th Gosei tournament, Kono Rin 9P (B) defeated Matsumoto Takehisa 7P by 1.5 points, so he will challenge Iyama Yuta Gosei for the title. Kono challenged Iyama for the Tengen title last November, but lost three straight; he will be hoping to improve on this record in what will be his first Gosei challenge. The title match starts on July 6.</span></span></span></p>
<p><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span><strong>New Professional Couple:</strong> On June 4, Suzuki Ayumi 6-dan and Rin Kanketsu 7-dan got married at a hotel </span></span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>in Karuizawa. Rin commented: “There’s a perfect balance of supply and demand in our marriage: I like composing life-and-death problems and my wife likes solving them.” As far as I know, this is the 16th marriage among Nihon Ki-in professionals.</span></span></span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/the-power-report-cho-u-wins-crucial-game-in-meijin-league-takao-takes-lead-in-honinbo-title-match-kono-to-challenge-iyama-for-gosei-title-new-professional-couple/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>AGA Board Nominations Closing Soon</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/aga-board-nominations-in-east-and-west-closing-soon/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/aga-board-nominations-in-east-and-west-closing-soon/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Chris Garlock</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184224</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Less than 10 days remain before nominations close for the 2013 AGA board elections. Incumbents Peter Celmer and Chris Kirschner are running to retain their seats in the Eastern and Western regions respectively. Nominations, including self-nominations are being accepted through&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"><span style="font-size: medium;">Less than 10 days remain before nominations close for the 2013 AGA board elections. Incumbents Peter Celmer and Chris Kirschner are running to retain their seats in the Eastern and Western regions respectively. Nominations, including self-nominations are being accepted through June 15 and should be sent to <a href="elections@usgo.org" rel="nofollow">elections@usgo.org</a></span></span></span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/aga-board-nominations-in-east-and-west-closing-soon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>New Huntsville Go Club Seeks Rocket Scientists</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/new-huntsville-go-club-seeks-rocket-scientists/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/new-huntsville-go-club-seeks-rocket-scientists/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Chris Garlock</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184226</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[The new Rocket City Go Club in the Huntsville, AL area has been founded “in the hope that we could lure some of the many NASA rocket scientists in the area into trying one of the world&#8217;s most ancient and&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">The new <a href="http://www.rocketcitygo.com/">Rocket City Go Club </a></span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">in the Huntsville, AL area has been founded “in the hope that we could lure some of the many NASA rocket scientists in the area into trying one of the world&#8217;s most ancient and fun board games” reports </span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">Adam LeCroy.<strong> “</strong></span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">Non rocket scientists are also welcome of course!” The club&#8217;s inaugural meeting will be June 17th at noon, at the Sinsaegae restuarant, 2701 Patton Rd SW, Huntsville, AL.<br />
<em>Got go club news? Get the word out! Email reports to us at <a href="journal@usgo.org" rel="nofollow">journal@usgo.org</a> </em></span></span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/new-huntsville-go-club-seeks-rocket-scientists/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>UK Taps Shodan Challenger Chris Bryant to Reverse Team Fortunes</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/uk-taps-shodan-challenger-chris-bryant-to-reverse-team-fortunes/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/uk-taps-shodan-challenger-chris-bryant-to-reverse-team-fortunes/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 23:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Tony Collman</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Go News]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184191</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[A new captain has been appointed to head up the British team for the online Pandanet Go European Team Championship 2013 following the UK’s demotion to the C League, after they failed to win a single game last season (A League&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new captain has been appointed to head up the British team for the online <a href="http://www.eurogofed.org/teams/index.htm">Pandanet Go European Team Championship</a> <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.06_ChrisBryant.png"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-184222" title="2013.06.06_ChrisBryant" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.06_ChrisBryant.png" alt="" width="280" height="280" /></a>2013 following the UK’s demotion to the C League, after they failed to win a single game last season <em>(<a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/a-league-finalists-set-in-european-team-championship/">A League Finalists Set in European Team Championship</a> 5/10 EJ).</em></p>
<p><a href="http://www.europeangodatabase.eu/EGD/Player_Card.php?key=16086862">Chris Bryant</a> 1d (pictured), a 23-year-old software engineer from Bury, who plays at <a href="http://stalbans-go.org.uk/">St Albans Go Club</a>, has been charged with reversing the team’s fortunes and his personal go history speaks of a man with the resolve to achieve his goals. Bryant learned go in February 2011 and early on made a commitment to try and reach dan grade within a year, signing up for the British Go Association (BGA)’s <a href="http://www.britgo.org/node/3744">Shodan Challenge</a>, where ambitious players are supported in a formal attempt to reach a specified higher grade within one year.</p>
<p>The puzzle-loving Bryant attributes his go success to solving an estimated 10,000 tsumego problems in a year &#8212; including about 1,000 in the first week alone, bringing him to 13-kyu &#8212; and in fact has only played about 300 actual games.</p>
<p>Bryant not only took the Challenge and met it, but also displayed his organizational flair by running the Shodan Challenge in 2011 – 2012 for the BGA. At that time there was an individual mentoring system, but this was difficult logistically and as Bryant explains, “The way [it] works at the moment is that there is a forum/Google group where people can post up games to be reviewed”. The BGA has also held closed teaching events for stronger players to improve. Bryant has already identified and made contact with more than the maximum pool of twelve (minimum six) strong players from which four will be selected for each round .</p>
<p>Outgoing captain <a href="http://www.europeangodatabase.eu/EGD/Player_Card.php?key=14337147">Andrew Simons</a> 4d continues to play a part in strengthening British go talent by giving lectures most Thursdays at 8pm in the British Room on the <a href="http://www.gokgs.com">KGS</a> go server. Bryant said of the lectures,  “These have helped a lot of people; it&#8217;s the kind of thing that I&#8217;d love to see more of. I give lectures myself, though mostly on Second Life &#8211; we have a go playing location there called <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?KidoGoClub">Kido Province</a> “</p>
<p>As for future ambitions, Bryant said, “I&#8217;d like to become British Champion one day &#8211; going to need lots more tsumego for that though ;). I&#8217;ve never had a dedicated teacher but there have been a few people who I&#8217;ve got advice from and I&#8217;m really appreciative of that. One of the things I like most about go is that strong people seem eager to teach others, and so the trend continues as those players themselves become stronger!”</p>
<p>This year’s Championship starts in September.</p>
<p><em>- Tony Collman</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/uk-taps-shodan-challenger-chris-bryant-to-reverse-team-fortunes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tan Xiao, Liu Xing, Shi Yue &amp; Lian Xio Blaze Into Changqi Cup Semi-Finals</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/tan-xiao-liu-xing-shi-yue-lian-xio-blaze-into-changqi-cup-semi-finals/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/tan-xiao-liu-xing-shi-yue-lian-xio-blaze-into-changqi-cup-semi-finals/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 02:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Annalia Linnan</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Events/Tournaments]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Go News]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Go Photos]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184159</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Preliminaries for the 10th Changqi Cup finished May 31 after three days of fierce matches. When the smoke cleared, Tan Xiao 7P, Liu Xing 7P, Shi Yue 9P, and Lian Xio 4P stood above the rest, including last year’s defending&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://gogameguru.com/remembering-ing-chang-ki-the-10th-changqi-cup/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+gogameguru+%28Go+Game+Guru%29"><img class="alignleft" style="margin: 5px;" src="http://gogameguru.com/i/2013/06/Liu-Xing-Gu-Li-10th-Changqi-Cup.jpg" alt="gu li &amp; liu xing" width="382" height="255" /></a>Preliminaries for the 10th Changqi Cup finished May 31 after three days of fierce matches. When the smoke cleared, Tan Xiao 7P, Liu Xing 7P, Shi Yue 9P, and Lian Xio 4P stood above the rest, including last year’s defending champions Chen Yaoye 9P and Tuo Jiaxi 3P. The finalist’s circle was especially sweet for Liu as he competed in 2007, 2008, and 2011 to no avail. However, this year he bested his two-time conqueror Gu Li 9P. No date has been set for the semifinals, although the finals have been scheduled for late October 2013.</p>
<p>Known as one of China’s “most generously sponsored tournaments” with a grand prize of over $73,000 USD, the Changqi Cup always draws China’s top players. Pros who made an appearance this year were Chang Hao 9P, Fan Tingyu 9P, Kong Jie 9P, and Jiang Weijie 9P, to name a few. Joint-hosts the Chinese Go Association and the Ing Foundation (Shanghai Branch) originally came together in 2004 to honor Ing Chang-ki. For more information about this year’s tournament including photos and game records, please visit <a href="http://gogameguru.com/remembering-ing-chang-ki-the-10th-changqi-cup/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+gogameguru+%28Go+Game+Guru%29">Go Game Guru</a>.<br />
<em>- Annalia S. Linnan, based on reporting on Go Game Guru</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/tan-xiao-liu-xing-shi-yue-lian-xio-blaze-into-changqi-cup-semi-finals/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>AGF Restocks, Publishes DIY 9&#215;9 Board</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/agf-restocks-publishes-diy-9x9-board/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/agf-restocks-publishes-diy-9x9-board/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 02:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Roy Laird</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184208</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[What does $17,000 buy? If you’re The American Go Foundation, here’s the answer: 8,000 9&#215;9 cardboard beginner boards for the Starter Set, 1,000 full size wooden boards for the Club Classic and 2,000 vinyl boards for distribution to AGF programs&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What does $17,000 buy? If you’re <a href="http://agfgo.org/" target="_blank">The American Go Foundation</a>, here’s the answer: 8,000 9&#215;9 cardboard beginner<a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.05_starter-kit.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-184213" style="margin: 5px;" title="2013.06.05_starter-kit" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.05_starter-kit.jpg" alt="" width="211" height="161" /></a> boards for the <a href="http://agfgo.org/pages/starter-set.php">Starter Set</a>, 1,000 full size wooden boards for the <a href="http://agfgo.org/pages/store-playing.php">Club Classic </a>and 2,000 <a href="http://agfgo.org/pages/store-teaching.php">vinyl boards</a> for distribution to AGF programs and AGA chapters. Thanks to generous donors, “We’ve provided hundreds of programs with materials in the last few years, and our successful outreach to <a href="http://agfgo.org/pages/schools.php">schools </a>and <a href="http://agfgo.org/pages/libraries.php">libraries </a>means that demand is growing even faster,” AGF VP Paul Barchilon told the EJ. For the DIYers out there, the AGF has also made the <a href="http://agfgo.org/downloads/AGArules9X9board.pdf" target="_blank">PDF</a> of the 9&#215;9 board available as a download. “Why didn’t we think of this before?” muses AGF President Terry Benson. “Print boards and rules, make stones from card stock with a ¾” punch (available online or at any good craft store) and you’re ready to go.” The AGF is supported entirely by generous go players; to support their work, <a href="http://agfgo.org/pages/donate.php" target="_blank">click here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/agf-restocks-publishes-diy-9x9-board/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Third International Children&#8217;s Art Contest</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/third-international-childrens-art-contest/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/third-international-childrens-art-contest/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 18:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Paul Barchilon</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Go Art]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S. Go Congress]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[World]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Youth]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184193</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[The popular International Children&#8217;s Go Art Contest is back for the third year in a row, and children are invited to submit their pieces.  Last year&#8217;s contest drew almost 70 entries, from ten different countries, and this year organizers hope&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/third-international-childrens-art-contest/screen-shot-2013-06-05-at-12-13-03-pm/" rel="attachment wp-att-184194"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-184194" style="margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" title="Screen shot 2013-06-05 at 12.13.03 PM" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Screen-shot-2013-06-05-at-12.13.03-PM.png" alt="" width="318" height="337" /></a>The popular International Children&#8217;s Go Art Contest is back for the third year in a row, and children are invited to submit their pieces.  Last year&#8217;s contest drew almost 70 entries, from ten different countries, and this year organizers hope to pull in even more.  The entries will be exhibited at the US Go Congress in Tacoma, in August.  The categories will be for under 12 and under 16, with three winners, and 2 notable entries in each category.  Magnetic go sets for the top six winners will be provided by <a href="http://www.ymimports.com/">Yellow Mountain Imports</a>.  To see some highlights of last year&#8217;s entries, visit the <a href="http://www.gosymposium.org/artcontest.html">online gallery</a> on the Go Symposium site.  The contest also has a Facebook page <a href="https://www.facebook.com/theartofgo">here</a>.  Complete entry information is available in the pdf file attached to this link (right click to download once it takes you to the page with the file) <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/third-international-childrens-art-contest/goartcontest2013/" rel="attachment wp-att-184195">GoArtContest2013</a>. -<em>Paul Barchilon, E-J Youth Editor</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/third-international-childrens-art-contest/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>“The Surrounding Game” Heads to Japan</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/the-surrounding-game-heads-to-japan/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/the-surrounding-game-heads-to-japan/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 16:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Chris Garlock</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Go Art]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184155</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Heading to Japan later this month, “The Surrounding Game” documentary crew is looking for help as they finish up principal photography on the film. The 3-man filming team will arrive in Tokyo on June 25 and shoot for about a&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Heading to Japan later this month, <a href="http://www.surroundinggamemovie.com/en/">“The Surrounding Game”</a> documentary crew is looking for help as they finish up principal photography on the film. The 3-man filming team will arrive in Tokyo on June 25 and shoot for about a week before heading to Osaka. “We are in communication with several people at the Nihon Kiin in Tokyo and the Kansai Kiin in Osaka,” reports Will Lockhart, “and we’re looking for people to stay with, interpreters, and other filming ideas that visually illustrate the rich cultural legacy of the game.” The Japan shoot “will be our last big filming operation, and I am confident it will lead to some of our very best material,” Lockhart adds. <a href="http://www.surroundinggamemovie.com/en/news/23">Click here</a> for the complete update and use the comment section to post suggestions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/the-surrounding-game-heads-to-japan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Garlock UK Walk Raises Nearly $2,000 for AGF</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/garlock-uk-walk-raises-nearly-2000-for-agf/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/garlock-uk-walk-raises-nearly-2000-for-agf/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 15:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Chris Garlock</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184140</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[“Lisa and I want to thank everyone who contributed so generously to the American Go Foundation through our recent Coast to Coast walk in England,” says American Go E-Journal Managing Editor Chris Garlock. “It turns out that many ‘Coasters’ do&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>“Lisa and I want to thank everyone who <a href="http://www.gofundme.com/Garlock-Walk-AGF">contributed so generously</a> to the <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.03_GarlockWalk.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-184141" style="margin: 5px;" title="2013.06.03_GarlockWalk" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.03_GarlockWalk.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="224" /></a>American Go Foundation through our recent Coast to Coast walk in England,” says <em>American Go E-Journal</em> Managing Editor Chris Garlock. “It turns out that many ‘Coasters’ do the walk as charity fundraisers and it gave us a great opportunity to talk about the terrific and effective work the AGF does promoting go in the U.S.” The Garlocks &#8212; who were celebrating their 30th wedding anniversary &#8212; have raised almost $2,000 so far to support the AGF&#8217;s outreach to thousands of American children in schools, libraries and community centers across the country. &#8220;Promoting go is a long journey, not unlike a trek across difficult terrain,&#8221; says AGF President Terry Benson. &#8220;Chris and Lisa have blazed an exciting new trail we hope others will follow.&#8221; Deadline for donations is this Sunday at midnight; <a href="http://www.gofundme.com/Garlock-Walk-AGF">click here to contribute</a> and to see the list of contributors. &#8220;A very special thanks to Paul Barchilon &#8212; assisted by Roger Schrag and Andy Okun &#8212; for excellent work on the <em>E-Journal</em> while I was away,&#8221; Garlock added.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/garlock-uk-walk-raises-nearly-2000-for-agf/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Your Move/Readers Write: Power’s Wrong Order?</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/your-movereaders-write-powers-wrong-order/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/your-movereaders-write-powers-wrong-order/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 14:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Chris Garlock</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[YOUR MOVE: Readers Write]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184178</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[“Kudos for your ongoing, seemingly tireless work,” writes Sunnyvale Chapter founder and organizer Jean de Maiffe. “You&#8217;ve certainly learned and grown over the years.” However, de Maiffe says, “I have a small quibble for you. I think The Power Report&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>“Kudos for your ongoing, seemingly tireless work,” writes Sunnyvale Chapter founder and organizer Jean de Maiffe. “You&#8217;ve certainly learned and grown over the years.” However, de Maiffe says, “I have a small quibble for you. I think <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/the-power-report-takao-evens-score-in-honinbo-kisei-leagues-kono-or-matsumoto-to-be-gosei-challenger/">The Power Report</a> <em>(June 2 EJ)</em> would have been more effective if it were in chronological order.  Putting the Honinbo information first makes rather weak the statement, ‘This win may have given him [Takao] some momentum for the Honinbo title match.’ I think that statement would have been more powerful if it were foreshadowing Takao&#8217;s later success in the Honinbo.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/your-movereaders-write-powers-wrong-order/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Hsiang Elected IMSA General Secretary, Urges Strong N.A. Players to Participate in 2013 SportAccord World Mind Games</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/hsiang-elected-imsa-general-secretary-urges-strong-n-a-players-to-participate-in-2013-sportaccord-world-mind-games/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/hsiang-elected-imsa-general-secretary-urges-strong-n-a-players-to-participate-in-2013-sportaccord-world-mind-games/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 22:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Chris Garlock</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[SportAccord World Mind Games]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[World]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184145</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Longtime International Go Federation and American Go Association official Thomas Hsiang (second from right) was elected General Secretary of the International Mind Sports Association (IMSA) at the 2013 SportAccord Convention held during the week of May 28 in St. Petersburg,&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Longtime International Go Federation and American Go Association official <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.03_Hsiang-Yuki.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-184147" title="2013.06.03_Hsiang-Yuki" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.03_Hsiang-Yuki.jpg" alt="" width="320" height="234" /></a>Thomas Hsiang <em>(second from right)</em> was elected General Secretary of the <a href="http://www.imsaworld.com/wp/">International Mind Sports Association</a> (IMSA) at the 2013 SportAccord Convention held during the week of May 28 in St. Petersburg, Russia. IMSA also announced that the 2013 and 2014 SportAccord World Mind Games (SAWMG) will be held December 12-18 in Beijing for both years. For 2013, North America is invited to send a three-man team and one female player to compete for a total prize fund of $400,000 USD. “For North American players, this will be the most lucrative international tournament,” Hsiang told the E-Journal. For example, the team would get $9,000 if they defeat Europe; the female player would get $2,000 if she places 8th; and the pair would get $5,000 if they defeat Europe. “The AGA is planning a selection tournament, possibly using the NAMT event, to select our representative,” Hsiang said. Strong players, especially pros with North American citizenship, are encouraged to make inquiries with the AGA tournament coordinator, at <a href="karoline.burrall@usgo.org" rel="nofollow">tournaments@usgo.org</a>. The IMSA executive committee also elected the following officials: President: Kirsan Ilyumzhinov (FIDE); Deputy President: Harry Otten (FMJD); Treasurer: Marc de Pauw (WBF). In addition, Geoffrey Borg (FIDE) was designated the Executive Director. <em>photo: Hsiang (second from right) with IGF Secretary General Yuki Shigeno (far right); photo by Ivan Vigano</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/hsiang-elected-imsa-general-secretary-urges-strong-n-a-players-to-participate-in-2013-sportaccord-world-mind-games/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Power Report: Takao Evens Score in Honinbo; Kisei Leagues; Kono or Matsumoto to be Gosei Challenger:</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/the-power-report-takao-evens-score-in-honinbo-kisei-leagues-kono-or-matsumoto-to-be-gosei-challenger/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/the-power-report-takao-evens-score-in-honinbo-kisei-leagues-kono-or-matsumoto-to-be-gosei-challenger/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 00:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Chris Garlock</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[World]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184122</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[by John Power,  Japan Correspondent for the American Go E-Journal
<strong>Takao Evens Score in Honinbo Title Match: &#8230;</strong>Takao Shinji 9P has a notoriously bad career record against Iyama Yuta Honinbo, but he has shown that past results may be irrelevant. After]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color: #222222;"><em>by John Power, </em><em> Japan Correspondent for the American Go E-Journal</em></span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">Takao Evens Score in Honinbo Title Match: </span></span></strong><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">Takao Shinji 9P has a notoriously bad career record against Iyama Yuta Honinb</span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">o, but he has shown that past results may be irrelevant. After losing the firs</span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">t game in his challenge for the 68th Honinbo <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.02_honinbo1.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-184124" title="2013.06.02_honinbo1" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.02_honinbo1.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="166" /></a>title, Takao roared back with a s</span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">trong win in the </span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">second, played on May 28 &amp; 29, so the match is level. </span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">There was plenty of </span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">drama in the game, with three important ko fights.  The f</span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">irst was worth over 50 points and led to a major trade, but neither side took </span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">the lead. Another big trade followed the second ko fight, but once again the g</span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">ame remained evenly poised. Shortly after this (on move 205), Iyama made a sma</span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">ll misjudgment , letting Takao take the lead. Iyama resorted to yet another ko</span></span><span style="color: #222222;"> </span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">but was unable to make up his deficit, so he resigned after 244 moves. </span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">The third game will be played on June 5 &amp; 6.</span></span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">Kisei Leagues: </span></span></strong><span><span><span style="color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif;">Two games were played in the 38th Kisei Leagues on May 23. In the final game</span> </span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>in the first round of the A League, two of the big guns in the league clashed. </span></span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>Takao Shinji 9P, the top-ranked player in the league, beat Hane Naoki 9P, who </span></span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>is the second-ranked player; taking white, Takao won by half a point. This wi</span></span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>n may have given him some momentum for the Honinbo title match. </span></span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>The B League was one game behind the A League. The game on the 23rd was a mat</span></span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>ch-up between two veteran players, Kobayashi Satoru 9P and Yamashiro Hiroshi 9</span></span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>P; the former is a former Kisei (beating Cho Chikun in 1995), and Yamashiro ca</span></span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>me within an ace of winning the title in 1992 (he had the lead late in the 7th </span></span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>game but lost it in the endgame). Taking black, Kobayashi beat Yamashiro by r</span></span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>esignation.</span></span></span><br />
<span style="color: #222222;">        </span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>The first round of the B League was completed on 30 May. Taking white, 25th H</span></span></span><span><span><span style="color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif;">oninbo Chikun (Cho Chikun) defeated Kono Rin 9P by resignation to make a good</span> </span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>start to this year’s league.</span></span></span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><strong>Kono or Matsumoto to be </strong>Gosei Challenger: </span></span></strong><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>The semifinals in the 38th Gosei tournament were held on May 23. In one, Mats</span></span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>umoto Takehisa 7P (W) beat Akiyama Jiro 9P by 1.5 points; in the other, Kono R</span></span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>in 9P (B) beat Cho Riyu 8P by half a point. Either Kono or Matsumoto will chal</span></span></span><span><span><span style="color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif;">lenge Iyama Yuta for the Gosei title, but we don’t have a date for the final</span> </span></span><span style="color: #222222;"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span>yet.</span></span></span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/the-power-report-takao-evens-score-in-honinbo-kisei-leagues-kono-or-matsumoto-to-be-gosei-challenger/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>U.S. Go Congress Calendar Posted</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/u-s-go-congress-calendar-posted/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/u-s-go-congress-calendar-posted/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 00:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Chris Garlock</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S. Go Congress]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184128</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Attendees at this year&#8217;s US Go Congress can start planning their daily activities now with the Congress&#8217; handy Google Calendar. The the 29th Annual US Go Congress is set for August 3-11 at Pacific Lutheran University in Tacoma, Washington, and&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Attendees at this year&#8217;s <a href="http://www.gocongress.org/">US Go Congress</a> can start planning their daily activities now with the Congress&#8217; handy <a href="http://www.gocongress.org/2013/content_categories/18">Google </a><a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.02_USGoCongressCalendar.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-184130" title="2013.06.02_USGoCongressCalendar" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.02_USGoCongressCalendar.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="227" /></a><a href="http://www.gocongress.org/2013/content_categories/18">Calendar</a>. The the 29th Annual US Go Congress is set for August 3-11 at Pacific Lutheran University in Tacoma, Washington, and the schedule includes the US Open, the largest annual go tournament in the US, professional lectures and game analysis, continuous self paired games, and all kinds of go-related activities from morning to midnight. Congress organizers credit “the talented work of Bart Jacob and Jared Beck” for the first-ever online calendar. “Remember, though, that the calendar is a dynamic production,” notes Gordon Castanza, “so come back to it now and then to see if there are any updates. We will strive to use this valuable tool during the Congress as well. So those with portable devices, laptops, tablets, etc. can see the calendar at any time.”<br />
<em><br />
</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/u-s-go-congress-calendar-posted/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Mexico City Beats Portland in Youth Team Rematch</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/mexico-city-beats-portland-in-youth-team-rematch/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/mexico-city-beats-portland-in-youth-team-rematch/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 21:28:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Chris Garlock</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Youth]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184101</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Mexico City, Mexico, beat Portland, Oregon 8-0 in a May 25 team match between elementary school players, taking revenge for their 8-4 loss the last time these two teams met up. Four players from Mexico City competed against eight Portland&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mexico City, Mexico, beat Portland, Oregon 8-0 in a May 25 team match between elementary school players, taking revenge for<a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.01_Mexico-Kids.jpg"><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-184104" title="2013.06.01_Mexico-Kids" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.01_Mexico-Kids-150x99.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="99" /></a> their 8-4 loss the last time these two teams met up. Four players from Mexico City competed <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.01_Portland-Kids.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-184105" style="margin: 5px;" title="2013.06.01_Portland-Kids" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/2013.06.01_Portland-Kids-150x112.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="112" /></a>against eight Portland players, with each Portland player playing one game and Mexico City players playing two games in this two-round match. Playing for Mexico City were Leo, Samuel, Dante and Diego. For Portland: Hikaru, Nicholas, Wilson, Aden, Jordan, Noah, Tyler and Cameron. This was the first match for Nicholas and Cameron.<br />
<em>- Peter Freedman; photos by Freedman (left, Portland) and Siddhartha Avila (right, Mexico City)</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/mexico-city-beats-portland-in-youth-team-rematch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Scottish Open Goes to Di Wu</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/scottish-open-goes-to-di-wu/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/scottish-open-goes-to-di-wu/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 21:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Tony Collman</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Go News]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184007</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Di Wu 4d of Durham, England triumphed over 24 other players in the Scottish Open tournament on May 25-26, winning his games in all six rounds. The runner-up, with five wins, was Scottish Champion David Lee 3d, of Dundee, Scotland.&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.europeangodatabase.eu/EGD/Player_Card.php?&amp;key=16774714">Di Wu</a> 4d of Durham, England triumphed over 24 other players in the <a href="http://www.britgo.org/tournaments/scottishopen">Scottish Open</a> tournament on May 25-26, winning his games in all six rounds. The runner-up, with five wins, was Scottish Champion David Lee 3d, of Dundee, Scotland. Jurriaan Dijkman 4k, of Skye, Scotland took third place.</p>
<p>Gary Craig 15k of Glasgow, Scotland also won five games and Martin Harvey 5k of Manchester, England, Greg Cox 10k of Dundee, Scotland and Carol Goodheir 11k of Skye all won four.</p>
<p>The tournament originated as the Edinburgh tournament in 1981. The Scottish Open later moved to Glasgow, Aberdeen and then Dundee, before returning to Glasgow this year &#8211; 14 years after it was last held there. The event took place at <a href="http://www.gla.ac.uk/">Glasgow University’s</a> Gilchrist Postgraduate Club. Six players who arrived early, on Friday evening, played simultaneous games against Di Wu.</p>
<p>Sadly, <a href="//www.europeangodatabase.eu/EGD/Player_Card.php?&amp;key=15737689”" rel="nofollow">Boris Mitrovic</a> 2k*, a resident of Edinburgh, Scotland (although Serbian by birth), was unable to play in the Scottish Open, as he was busy in London, challenging for the British Championship (see <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/simons-to-challenge-kay-for-british-championship/">E-J of May 28</a>). He said: &#8220;I think it&#8217;s unfortunate the Scottish Open collided with this tournament, as there are very few go tournaments one can play which are near Edinburgh. If they didn&#8217;t collide I&#8217;d play in both&#8221;.</p>
<p>Ironically, as reported in the <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/andrew-kay-on-course-to-retain-british-championship/"> E-J of May 10</a>, the Candidates Tournament, from which Mitrovic qualified for the Challengers&#8217; League, was held in his home town in order to encourage more Scottish players to enter for the Championship.</p>
<p>As the Bard of Scotland, Rabbie Burns, put it: &#8220;The best laid schemes o&#8217; mice an&#8217; men/Gang aft a-gley**&#8221;</p>
<p>Click here for <a href="http://www.britgo.org/results/2013/scottish.html">full results</a>.</p>
<p><em>-Tony Collman. </em><em>Compiled from material on the <a href="http://www.britgo.org/">BGA’s website</a> and sources.</em></p>
<p><em>* This rating was given after Mitrovic played in mainland Europe (Poland) last year, where there is a discrepancy with British grades. As his performance at the Challengers&#8217; League demonstrates, he is well able to play at least to the standard of his BGA Shodan certificate.<br />
</em>** often go awry</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/scottish-open-goes-to-di-wu/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Go Classified: Books For Sale</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/go-classified-books-for-sale-3/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/go-classified-books-for-sale-3/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 20:46:02 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Chris Garlock</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Go Classified]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184098</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Looking to sell part of my go book collection of several hundred. Starting off with beginner books, but can search library for specific books upon request. List, prices, and ordering information here.
- Lawrence Ku&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Looking to sell part of my go book collection of several hundred. Starting off with beginner books, but can search library for specific books upon request. <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0AqAsvDyYLsgKdEZhMGhJdUlOMjlPTFgyNGEteXNtOFE&amp;usp=sharing">List, prices, and ordering information here</a>.<br />
<em>- Lawrence Ku</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/06/go-classified-books-for-sale-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Eric Lui 7D Sweeps 40th Maryland Open</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/eric-lui-7d-sweeps-40th-maryland-open/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/eric-lui-7d-sweeps-40th-maryland-open/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:38:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Chris Garlock</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184060</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<strong>&#8230;</strong>An undefeated Eric Lui 7D won the 2013 Maryland Open and NAMT Qualifier, held May 25-26 in Baltimore, MD. A total of 52 players &#8220;enjoyed beautiful weather for the 40th Maryland Open,&#8221; reports organizer Keith Arnold. Eight players 4-dan and]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong></strong>An undefeated Eric Lui 7D won the 2013 Maryland Open and NAMT Qualifier, held May 25-26 in Baltimore, MD. A total of 52 players &#8220;enjoyed beautiful weather for the 40th Maryland Open,&#8221; reports organizer Keith Arnold. Eight players 4-dan and above competed for NAMT points. Gurujeet Khalsa directed the 5-round event.</p>
<p><em><strong>Winner&#8217;s Report:</strong></em> Open Section: Eric Lui 7 dan (undefeated); 2nd Yuan Zhou 7 dan; 3rd Daniel Chou 6 dan<br />
A Section: Justin Ching 4 dan; 2nd Willis Huang 3 dan<br />
B Section: Kelsey Dyer 1 dan; 2nd Ken Koester 2 dan<br />
C Section: Julian Erville 2 kyu and Kyu Champion; 2nd Todd Blatt 1 kyu<br />
D Section: Nathan Epstein 5 kyu (undefeated); 2nd Arnold Eudell 4 kyu<br />
E Section: Andrew Liu 6 kyu; 2nd Frederick Bao, (The Smiling Assassin, 6 years old) 6 kyu<br />
F Section: Bob Crites 10 kyu; 2nd Roberto Andaya 12 kyu<br />
Fighting Spirit Prize &#8211; Leslie Lamphere 12 kyu</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/eric-lui-7d-sweeps-40th-maryland-open/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Chapel Hill Chinese School Team &amp; Changlong Wu 7d Top Carolina Spring Go Tournament</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/chapel-hill-chinese-school-team-changlong-wu-7d-top-carolina-spring-go-tournament/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/chapel-hill-chinese-school-team-changlong-wu-7d-top-carolina-spring-go-tournament/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 23:46:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Chris Garlock</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184063</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[The 10th annual Carolina Spring Go Tournament featured a hotly-contested team competition for the youth players. Four teams representing Raleigh Academy of Chinese Language (RACL), Cary Chinese School (CCS) and Chinese School at Chapel Hill (CSCH) competed in the team&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 10th annual Carolina Spring Go Tournament featured a hotly-contested <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/2013.05.30_NC-Team_Champion.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-184066" title="2013.05.30_NC-Team_Champion" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/2013.05.30_NC-Team_Champion-239x300.jpg" alt="" width="239" height="300" /></a>team competition for the youth players. Four teams representing Raleigh Academy of Chinese Language (RACL), Cary Chinese School (CCS) and Chinese School at Chapel Hill (CSCH) competed in the team tournament at the May 18 event, held in Raleigh, North Carolina and organized by the Cary Go Club and the Chinese-American Friendship Association of North Carolina. The tournament attracted 30 go players with ages ranging from 6 to 70 years old.</p>
<p>&#8220;The team competition was fierce,&#8221; reports organizer Owen Chen. &#8220;Young players kept reporting and checking the team scores posted on the wall after each round. In the end, the Chinese School at Chapel Hill team consisting of Justin Zhang, Andrew Huan and their teacher Eric Zhang (right) won the team <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/2013.05.30_NC_Individual_Champion_Changlong_Wu.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-184067" style="margin: 5px;" title="2013.05.30_NC_Individual_Champion_Changlong_Wu" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/2013.05.30_NC_Individual_Champion_Changlong_Wu-198x300.jpg" alt="" width="198" height="300" /></a>competition.&#8221;</p>
<p>In the individual competition, a new Duke student, Liqun Liu, who was a 5 dan in China, gave long-term North Carolina champion Changlong Wu 7d (left) a fierce challenge. Wu won the close match against Liu and eventually won the open section with a perfect score of 4-0. Liu finished the second place in the open section with his only loss to Wu.</p>
<p>Xiaoping Wu 1d won Section A (1d-2d) with a perfect score of 4-0. John Zhu 9k won Section B (9k-1k) with a score of 3-1. Tom Carlson 10k topped Section C (15k-10k) with a perfect score of 4-0. Justin Zhang 19k, who was a member of the Chinese School at Chapel Hill team that won the team competition, also won the indiviual champion in Section D (25k-16k) with a 4-0 score.<br />
<em>- photos courtesy Owen Chen </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/chapel-hill-chinese-school-team-changlong-wu-7d-top-carolina-spring-go-tournament/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Transatlantic Youth Match Sunday June 2</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/transatlantic-youth-match-sunday-june-2/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/transatlantic-youth-match-sunday-june-2/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 22:43:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Paul Barchilon</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Youth]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184081</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[The fifth annual Transatlantic Youth Tournament will take place Sunday on KGS.  Ten young players from Europe will face off against ten from North America, the team with the most wins will be the victor (captain&#8217;s game will be the&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<div>The fifth annual Transatlantic Youth Tournament will take place Sunday on KGS.  Ten young players from Europe will face off against ten from North America, the team with the most wins will be the victor (captain&#8217;s game will be the tiebreak if needed).  North America won last year, with an overwhelming 8-2 finish, and the Europeans are itching for paybacks this time around.  Most of the matches will be held Sunday June 3, in the Transatlantic Youth Go room on KGS (under tournaments).  The schedule will be:</div>
<div>
<div>
<div>13:00 UCT/GMT:</div>
<div>       1. Andrew Huang (donvalley) &#8211; Jonas Welticke</div>
<div>15:00 UCT/GMT:<br />
2. Jianing Gan (hkkyeen) &#8211; Alexander Vashurov (ALEX575)</div>
</div>
<div>         3. Yunxuan Li &#8211; Stepan Popov (StepanP)</div>
<div>         4. Aaron Ye (hyperbeam7) &#8211; Denis Dobranis</div>
<div>         5. Oliver Wolf (sinsai) &#8211; Schayan Hamrach (schayan355)</div>
<div>
<div></div>
<div>18:00 UCT/GMT<br />
6. Calvin Sun (kbag)  &#8211; Pavol Lisy (cheater)</div>
<div>        7. Bill Lin (billlin) &#8211; Lukas Podpera (Lukan)</div>
<div>        8. Lionel Zhang  - Tanguy le Calve (Welvang)</div>
<div>        9. David Lu  - Valeriy Kulishov</div>
<div></div>
<div>4:00 UCT/GMT, Monday, 3rd June</div>
<div>       10. Hugh Zhang (sume) &#8211; Mateusz Surma (drakula)</div>
</div>
</div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="color: #000000; font-family: 'Lucida Grande'; line-height: normal; font-size: medium;"><br />
</span></div>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/transatlantic-youth-match-sunday-june-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>KBA Names Two Pros for US Go Congress</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/kba-names-two-pros-for-us-go-congress/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/kba-names-two-pros-for-us-go-congress/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 19:07:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Paul Barchilon</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S. Go Congress]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[World]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Youth]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184042</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[The Korea Baduk Association is sending Kim Hyunghwan 6p and Lee Dahye 4p to the US Go Congress in Tacoma this year. Kim Hyunghwan, 27, is a student of famed teacher Kapyong Kwon, whose students include Lee Sedol 9p and&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/kba-names-two-pros-for-us-go-congress/screen-shot-2013-05-29-at-12-00-20-pm/" rel="attachment wp-att-184043"><img class="alignright  wp-image-184043" style="margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" title="Screen shot 2013-05-29 at 12.00.20 PM" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Screen-shot-2013-05-29-at-12.00.20-PM-300x288.png" alt="" width="240" height="230" /></a>The Korea Baduk Association is sending Kim Hyunghwan 6p and Lee Dahye 4p to the US Go Congress in Tacoma this year. Kim Hyunghwan, 27, is a student of famed teacher Kapyong Kwon, whose students include Lee Sedol 9p and Park Junghwan 9p. He distinguished himself as a youth player, and was unbeaten in the 2001 WYGC in Maui, Hawaii, becoming pro the following year. The Maui experience  prompted him to study English. He is also a student of Chinese and teaches go at university clubs. Lee Dahye, 28, aside from representing Korea in international play, is a specialist at teaching beginners, expertise she will be sharing as an instructor at the first ever AGA classroom teaching certification workshop at Congress. Since 2008, Lee has amassed an impressive record broadcasting lessons on Baduk TV, K-Baduk and Cyberoro (you can see some of her lessons on YouTube <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rVmCUPfAlW8)">here</a>).  She has also taught soldiers in Korea&#8217;s military, students at university clubs, and multicultural youth. She  edited the Korean edition of <em>Hikaru no go</em> as well. Most relevant for the teaching workshop, she is co-author of the Korean-English go book, <em>Falling in Love with Baduk,</em> which will be distributed to workshop students free in PDF form (it is available for download through the AGF <a href="http://agfgo.org/pages/bookoffers.php">here</a> as well). She graduated Hankuk University of Foreign Studies, majoring in Japanese, and is in graduate school in the same university.<em> -Andy Okun, with assistance from Myungwan Kim 9p. Photo: Lee Dahye 4p</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/kba-names-two-pros-for-us-go-congress/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Virtual Go a Labor of Love for Games Programmer</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/virtual-go-a-labor-of-love-for-games-programmer/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/virtual-go-a-labor-of-love-for-games-programmer/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 18:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Paul Barchilon</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Tools: books, software & hardware]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=184028</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[When Glenn Fiedler first came to go in 2004, he was immediately taken with the aesthetic side of the game, the black and white stones, their biconvex shape, the sound they make hitting a wooden board.  “I especially loved the&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/virtual-go-a-labor-of-love-for-games-programmer/screen-shot-2013-05-29-at-11-19-46-am-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-184030"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-184030" style="margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" title="Screen shot 2013-05-29 at 11.19.46 AM" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Screen-shot-2013-05-29-at-11.19.46-AM1-600x443.png" alt="" width="288" height="213" /></a>When Glenn Fiedler first came to go in 2004, he was immediately taken with the aesthetic side of the game, the black and white stones, their biconvex shape, the sound they make hitting a wooden board.  “I especially loved the way go stones wobble and how stone placement becomes irregular as the game progresses, because the go stones are just slightly larger than the grid,” he told the EJ.  Playing on a computer, though, was not the same experience.  “When I play go on a computer it feels like I&#8217;m playing on a magnetic board. In real life, I don&#8217;t want to play on a magnetic board. I wanted to make a go board that I could play on the computer that felt like I was really playing go.&#8221;  The desire led the Australian Fiedler to a career change.  He became a network game programmer with a specialization in physics and started developing methods of synchronizing physics simulations across multiple computers.  “I ended up inventing new techniques and talking at GDC (Game Developers Conference) about how to network physics simulations. And all the techniques I invented were originally thought up because I wanted to network a simulation of a go board and stones!&#8221;</p>
<p>Now, after finishing work on his latest project at Sony, “God of War: Ascension,” Fiedler has finally turned his attention to programming go.  The idea is not to provide an AI opponent, but instead provide a beautiful and compelling simulation of an actual 3D goban and stones that other developers could include in existing go software like SmartGo or Many Faces of Go, Fiedler said.  It is a painstaking step-by-step effort he is chronicling in a blog on his website, <a href="http://gafferongames.com/virtualgo/introduction-to-virtual-go/">Gaffer on Games. </a> The blog lays out the code and the physical reasoning behind it.  Fiedler hopes to make some commercial use of the software eventually, though it will be hard to do.  In the meantime, that’s not what’s on his mind. “I&#8217;ve had some time to work on my dream project after almost 10 years. It&#8217;s really satisfying.” <em>-Andy Okun.  Diagram of a stone from Fiedler&#8217;s blog: <a href="http://gafferongames.com/virtualgo/introduction-to-virtual-go/">Gaffer on Games.</a></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/virtual-go-a-labor-of-love-for-games-programmer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Go Spotting:  Go Builds Math Skills</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/go-spotting-go-builds-math-skills/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/go-spotting-go-builds-math-skills/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 18:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Myron Souris</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Go Spotting]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=183938</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[A recent article on the Business Insider website extols the mathematical benefits of the game of go, which is the 6th of 13 Things That You Can Do To Make Your Child A Genius At Math.
The article asked professional&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/EJ_math_go.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-183939" style="margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" title="EJ_math_go" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/EJ_math_go-300x224.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="224" /></a>A recent article on the <em>Business Insider</em> website extols the mathematical benefits of the game of go, which is the 6th of <em>13 Things That You Can Do To Make Your Child A Genius At Math</em>.</p>
<p>The article asked professional mathematicians what got them started in math. &#8221;<em>There is no better way to train your brain, said one respondent, than the game [of] Go.</em>&#8221;</p>
<p>Can you tell who is ahead in the go position that the article displays?  (Assume Black to play and a komi of 6.5.)  The full article appears <a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/how-to-make-your-child-love-math-2013-5?op=1">here</a>. <em>Thanks to Chris Sira for sending the link.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/go-spotting-go-builds-math-skills/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>AGA Election Update</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/aga-election-update/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/aga-election-update/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 15:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Paul Barchilon</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=183901</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Incumbent Paul Celmer has been nominated to retain his seat as eastern region representative. No nominations for western or central region candidates have been received yet.  Nominations close June 15 and should be sent to elections@usgo.org. Qualifications and procedures are here http://www.usgo.org/aga-board-elections.&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Incumbent Paul Celmer has been nominated to retain his seat as eastern region representative. No nominations for western or central region candidates have been received yet.  Nominations close June 15 and should be sent to <a href="mailto:elections@usgo.org">elections@usgo.org</a>. Qualifications and procedures are here <a href="http://www.usgo.org/aga-board-elections">http://www.usgo.org/aga-board-elections</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/aga-election-update/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Simons to Challenge Kay for British Championship</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/simons-to-challenge-kay-for-british-championship/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/simons-to-challenge-kay-for-british-championship/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 00:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Paul Barchilon</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=183949</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Reigning British Champion, Andrew Kay 4d, and fellow Cambridge University graduate Andrew Simons 4d, have emerged as the finalists for the British Go Championship from this weekend&#8217;s Challengers&#8217; League. Simons is the Terry Stacey Grand Prix 2013 title-holder (awarded for best tournament results over&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/simons-to-challenge-kay-for-british-championship/kay/" rel="attachment wp-att-183978"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-183978" style="margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" title="kay" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/kay-600x391.jpg" alt="" width="360" height="235" /></a>Reigning British Champion, <a href="http://andrewkay.name/go/">Andrew Kay</a> 4d, and fellow Cambridge University graduate <a href="http://www.europeangodatabase.eu/EGD/Player_Card.php?key=14337147 ">Andrew Simons</a> 4d, have emerged as the finalists for the <a href="http://www.britgo.org/bchamp/index.html">British Go Championship</a> from this weekend&#8217;s <a href="http://www.britgo.org/tournaments/challengersleague">Challengers&#8217; League</a>. Simons is the <a href="http://www.britgo.org/hof/stacey.html">Terry Stacey Grand Prix</a> 2013 title-holder (awarded for best tournament results over the year to the British Go Congress last April). The pair will meet for the best-of-three final at a time and place yet to be fixed, to decide who will take the title of British Champion. As both players intend to travel to Asia over the next three months, the final will probably not take place before August. When it does happen, it is likely to be followed live in the British Room on the KGS go server, with professional commentary.</p>
<p>In the Challengers League, which ran from Friday till Monday, each of the eight most successful players from the Candidates&#8217; Tournament (see the <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/andrew-kay-on-course-to-retain-british-championship/">EJ from May </a> 10th), held earlier this month in Edinburgh, played one game against each other, with 1 hour 45 minutes main time each and 15 stones in 5 minutes repeating overtime. Under British Go Association (BGA) rules, the current title-holder was required to play in the Challengers&#8217; League on the same terms as the other seven, and in fact Kay also waived his right to be entered automatically, winning his place at the Candidates&#8217; Tournament as the others did. He said of this decision, &#8220;I&#8217;m always keen for an opportunity to play a high-level game of go with a reasonably long playing time and I like Edinburgh&#8221;. The other six challengers, in order of score, were: <a href="http://www.europeangodatabase.eu/EGD/Player_Card.php?key=15098028">Alex Kent</a> 2d, <a href="http://www.europeangodatabase.eu/EGD/Player_Card.php?key=10262032">Alex Rix</a> 2d, <a href="http://www.europeangodatabase.eu/EGD/Player_Card.php?key=10262043">Des Cann</a> 4d, <a href="http://www.europeangodatabase.eu/EGD/Player_Card.php?key=15737689">Boris Mitrovic</a> 2k, <a href="http://www.europeangodatabase.eu/EGD/Player_Card.php?&amp;key=10286034">Francis Roads</a> 1d, and <a href="http://www.europeangodatabase.eu/EGD/Player_Card.php?key=10613284 ">Tim Hunt</a> 2d.</p>
<p>The Challengers&#8217; League was held in the Nash Room and elsewhere at the International Student House, London and the British Championship 2013 is organized by Jenny Radcliffe on behalf of the BGA. Ms Radcliffe also expressed pride at the excellent showing by Alex Kent, whom she herself taught to play in Durham less than 10 years ago. Click <a href="http://www.britgo.org/results/2013/chall.html">here</a> for full results. <em>-Story and photo by Tony Collman.  Photo: Andrew Simons (l) vs. Andrew Kay (r)</em></p>
<p><span style="font-size: large;"><strong><br />
</strong></span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/simons-to-challenge-kay-for-british-championship/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Triple Ko in Tiger&#8217;s Mouth Tourney</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/triple-ko-in-tigers-mouth-tourney/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/triple-ko-in-tigers-mouth-tourney/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 21:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Paul Barchilon</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Youth]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=183961</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[An interesting triple ko came up in the most recent Tiger&#8217;s Mouth prize tourney.  The tourneys are run every month, and are open to youth in the US and Canada. Handicapped, and with prizes in double-digit kyu, single-digit kyu, and&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<p><a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/triple-ko-in-tigers-mouth-tourney/screen-shot-2013-05-27-at-2-15-51-pm/" rel="attachment wp-att-183963"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-183963" style="margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" title="Screen shot 2013-05-27 at 2.15.51 PM" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Screen-shot-2013-05-27-at-2.15.51-PM.png" alt="" width="249" height="156" /></a>An interesting triple ko came up in the most recent <a href="http://tigersmouth.org/forum/viewforum.php?forum_id=22">Tiger&#8217;s Mouth prize tourney</a>.  The tourneys are run every month, and are open to youth in the US and Canada. Handicapped, and with prizes in double-digit kyu, single-digit kyu, and dan sections, the tourneys provide challenging games for players of all levels, with prizes courtesy of the AGF.  The triple ko came up in a six stone game between Narnian 12k, and Gocookrice 18k, and can be seen in the attached game record. The ruleset was Japanese, which technically means the game should be no result. The players asked the TD to make a ruling, he decided it was a seki, and gave the win to white on territory.  How would the triple ko have been resolved in other rule sets?  The E-J asked Yilun Yang 7p to weigh in with Chinese rules: &#8220;If both players keep taking the ko in this situation, it seems the game should be no-result. Black has to keep capturing,  otherwise black loses. Unless one side gives up the ko battle, no one can win, and neither player can give up the ko in this game.&#8221;</p>
<p>AGA rules resolve the issue by making full board repetition illegal, which turns this situation into what is called &#8220;<a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?Superko">Super Ko</a>&#8220;. AGA Rules Coordinator Terry Benson says: &#8220;The main point of AGA rules is that the players have to figure and play it out &#8211; not the ref &#8211; and we have no null games. A triple ko is going to prohibit the 6th move. So who starts matters. Thus finding a ko threat on move 6 which the opponent answers, would reset the triple ko with the other player to start. I think Ing rules would be the same. This is a fighting ko.&#8221; See move 257 to illustrate the options.</p>
<p>E-J Games Editor Myron Souris has a succinct analysis for this situation: &#8220;according to AGA rules Black wins the triple ko, no matter who plays first.  If Black takes 1st, then 6 moves later White would be forbidden from repeating the position from just before Black&#8217;s 1st move.  So White dies.  And White taking the triple ko 1st is useless, because Black is alive in double ko. With the AGA rules, Terry and the rules committee devised a truly beautiful ruleset:  simple, rigorous, and sensible. Numerous people have unfairly criticized the AGA ruleset for being to difficult to apply to these multiple ko situations, e.g., &#8216;Knowing when a previous board position repeats is too difficult.&#8217;  Terry&#8217;s analysis exposes that misconception for this game.  A few years ago, I found about a dozen pro games (the latest is the infamous <a href="http://gogameguru.com/go-commentary-gu-li-vs-lee-sedol-quadruple-ko-game-17th-samsung-cup/">2012 Gu Li vs. Lee Sedol game</a>) ending in triple and quadruple ko, all of which even I could apply the AGA rules to resolve who would have won without too much work. Yes, some contrived multiple ko situations can be extremely difficult to analyze for who wins; however, those situations don&#8217;t seem to appear in real games, and in any event, the AGA allows the players to play out the situation themselves.&#8221;<em> </em>To sign up for the next Tiger&#8217;s Mouth Tourney, on June 15th, <a href="http://tigersmouth.org/forum/viewforum.php?forum_id=22">click here</a>.<em> -Paul Barchilon, E-J Youth Editor </p>
<p><a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/?attachment_id=183971">download SGF file</a></p>
<p></em></p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/triple-ko-in-tigers-mouth-tourney/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Podpera, Hui, and Pittner Lead Fifth Kido Cup in Hamburg</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/podpera-hui-and-pittner-lead-fifth-kido-cup-in-hamburg/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/podpera-hui-and-pittner-lead-fifth-kido-cup-in-hamburg/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 03:42:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Roger Schrag</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=183905</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[The fifth annual Kido Cup was held in Hamburg, Germany May 18-20. The three day event, including a main tournament, top group, and kids tournament, has become the largest go event held in Germany. In addition to the tournaments, this&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-183906" title="" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/kido_cup-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" />The fifth annual Kido Cup was held in Hamburg, Germany May 18-20. The three day event, including a main tournament, top group, and kids tournament, has become the largest go event held in Germany. In addition to the tournaments, this year&#8217;s Kido Cup also featured numerous side events, including six visiting pros from Korea playing teaching games and giving game reviews. Lukas Podpera 5d was the champion at the main tournament among a field of 198 players. Full main tournament results are available <a href="http://www.eurogotv.com/tournament/showresults.php?toernooicode=T130518I">here</a>. Fan Hui 2p, a pro from China living in France since 2000, won the top group with a 6-1 record. Top group results are available <a href="http://www.eurogotv.com/tournament/showresults.php?toernooicode=T130518J">here</a>. Arved Pittner 5k from Berlin won the kids tournament. Full results are available <a href="http://www.dgob.de/tourn/tourn.cgi?f=13dekiki.txt&amp;mode=cml">here</a>.  <em>Story by Jan Engelhardt, photo by Joachim Beggerow.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/podpera-hui-and-pittner-lead-fifth-kido-cup-in-hamburg/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Mlily Cup Preliminaries</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/mlily-cup-preliminaries/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/mlily-cup-preliminaries/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 03:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Paul Barchilon</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[World]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=183887</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[The preliminary rounds for the first Mlily Cup concluded May 24th, in Beijing, China.  The cup is organized by the International Go Federation (IGF) and the China Qiyuan, and sponsored by Hengkang Jiaju Technology Company.  The cup is held every other year, thus&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/mlily-cup-preliminaries/5a0453a8-f33c-4e96-8a7a-323dd0c67d71/" rel="attachment wp-att-183889"><img class="alignright  wp-image-183889" style="margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" title="5a0453a8-f33c-4e96-8a7a-323dd0c67d71" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/5a0453a8-f33c-4e96-8a7a-323dd0c67d71-600x365.jpg" alt="" width="360" height="219" /></a>The preliminary rounds for the first Mlily Cup concluded May 24th, in Beijing, China.  The cup is organized by the International Go Federation (IGF) and the China Qiyuan, and sponsored by Hengkang Jiaju Technology Company.  The cup is held every other year, thus supplementing the other IGF-organized biannual tournament: the Bailing Cup. With a top prize of RMB 1.8 M (about USD 280K), Mlily ranks near the top of all international titles.  Just as in Bailing, the Mlily Cup takes on an &#8221;open&#8221; format:  All professionals may enter in the preliminary rounds; as may all amateurs after winning online selection tournaments.   Ryan Li won the selection tournament from North America, and was the US amateur representative.  Jujo (Zhujiu) Jiang 9P entered as an American pro; while Rui Naiwei 9P entered as a Chinese pro.  All three lost in the first round.  The popular Joanne Missingham 6P(Hei Jia-jia) entered as a Taiwanese pro, and won her section of 11 players, to move on to the main tournament.  <em>- Report by Thomas Hsiang. Photo from the <a href="http://www.hkfoam.com/News/news-1.aspx?id=83&amp;english=e" target="_blank">Mlily website</a>: Zhang Xuan 8p (l) </em><em>has been one of the top female players in China. She</em> is married to Chang Hao 9P.  Joanne Missingham 6P (r) is leading a new generation of strong young female players; she is representing Taiwian.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/mlily-cup-preliminaries/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Go Spotting: Chinese Military Fantasy Novels</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/go-spotting-chinese-military-fantasy-novels/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/go-spotting-chinese-military-fantasy-novels/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 03:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Roger Schrag</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Go Spotting]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=183913</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[An article in the May 23 issue of the magazine Foreign Policy entitled &#8220;Pulp Liberation Army&#8221; surveys the strange and terrifying underground world of Chinese military fantasy novels. One such novel, 2066: Red Star Over America, &#8220;portrays the United States&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-183914" title="" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/fp-150x122.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="122" />An article in the May 23 issue of the magazine <em>Foreign Policy</em> entitled &#8220;Pulp Liberation Army&#8221; surveys the strange and terrifying underground world of Chinese military fantasy novels. One such novel, <em>2066: Red Star Over America</em>, &#8220;portrays the United States in the throes of a Cultural Revolution, where bands of marauding U.S. students fight battles in the country&#8217;s ravaged countryside. China is the world&#8217;s top superpower, and an earthquake has sunk Japan, erasing it from the map. The protagonist, a Chinese Go player and diplomatic envoy, tries to return civilization to a crumbling United States.&#8221; Go player to the rescue! Read the full article <a href="http://www.foreignpolicy.com/articles/2013/05/23/chinese_military_liberation_novels?page=0,1">here</a>. <em>Thank you Matthew Curran for sharing this.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/go-spotting-chinese-military-fantasy-novels/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Summer Go Camp</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/summer-go-camp/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/summer-go-camp/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 19:59:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Paul Barchilon</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Youth]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=183879</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[The AGA Summer Go Camp will be held  at YMCA Camp T. Frank Soles in Rockwood, Pennsylvania, from July 20 to July 27. &#8220;Go Camp was a wonderful experience,&#8221; writes Sathya Anand 1k, who attended last year, &#8221; I feel my understanding of the&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/summer-go-camp/img_1744/" rel="attachment wp-att-183881"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-183881" style="margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" title="IMG_1744" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/IMG_1744-600x490.jpg" alt="" width="360" height="294" /></a>The AGA Summer Go Camp will be held  at YMCA Camp T. Frank Soles in Rockwood, Pennsylvania, from July 20 to July 27. &#8220;Go Camp was a wonderful experience,&#8221; writes Sathya Anand 1k, who attended last year, &#8221; I feel my understanding of the subtle complexities of go has been heightened considerably. I loved that everyone in my immediate vicinity had the same passion for learning that I had. I learned a boatload of joseki, as well as the ability to pinpoint where I needed to improve.&#8221;</p>
<div> &#8221;I loved the fact that everyone there was a go player just like myself,&#8221; writes Shawn Ray 4d, &#8220;I had fun doing activities with everyone while also studying go. I feel like I improved a good bit because the teachers broke me of my bad habits, and I think that really helped me focus my moves, and to play on a higher level.&#8221;</div>
<p>&#8220;If you&#8217;re a go player between the ages of 8 and 18, and would like an opportunity to study with a professional teacher for a week, the AGA Go Camp is for you,&#8221; says Camp Director Amanda Miller. Yilun Yang 7P will be the teacher this year. He has trained many notable players, including Rui Naiwei 9P and Chang Hao 9P. Anyone who played in the US Youth Go Championships can get a $400 AGF scholarship to the camp.  If you didn&#8217;t play, but need financial help to attend, you can apply for a needs based scholarship <a href="http://agfgo.org/pages/scholarships.php#summerscholarship" target="_blank">here.</a>  Please visit the <a href="http://www.gocampeast.org/" target="_blank">camp website</a> for registration information, or email the camp at <a href="mailto:agagocampeast@gmail.com" target="_blank">agagocampeast@gmail.com</a>. <em>-Paul Barchilon, E-J Youth Editor. Photo by Amanda Miller: Campers at last year&#8217;s event, in Black Mountain, NC.</em></p>
<div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/summer-go-camp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>KBA Donates Free Beginner&#8217;s Book to AGA</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/kba-donates-free-beginners-book-to-aga/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/kba-donates-free-beginners-book-to-aga/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 01:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Roy Laird</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Tools: books, software & hardware]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Youth]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=183760</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[With the publication of Falling in Love with Baduk: Play a Game in One Week, The Korea Baduk Association has taken yet another important step to support Western go.  Written in both Korean and English by Dahye Lee and Jihee&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/kba-donates-free-beginners-book-to-aga/screen-shot-2013-05-15-at-11-44-30-pm/" rel="attachment wp-att-183791"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-183791" title="Screen shot 2013-05-15 at 11.44.30 PM" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Screen-shot-2013-05-15-at-11.44.30-PM-202x300.png" alt="" width="202" height="300" /></a>With the publication of Falling in Love with Baduk: Play a Game in One Week, The <a href="http://english.baduk.or.kr/">Korea Baduk Association </a>has taken yet another important step to support Western go.  Written in both Korean and English by Dahye Lee and Jihee Baek, two young Korean pros, this is a book aimed at beginners, and especially Westerners. “People with different skin colors and different languages can understand one another when seated across the Baduk board,” they write.  “It thrills us to imagine a view of Easterners and Westerners playing the game together.” This is a valuable book for serious newcomers of any age. Basic principles are broken down into seven simple lessons, presumably one per day, with dozens of problems illustrating each day’s lesson. Ms. Lee will attend this year’s <a href="http://www.gocongress.org/2013/">US Go Congress</a> and will participate in the AGA’s first teacher training program. The book is ideal for classroom situations too, and can be used as a manual for non-players who find themselves running go programs at libraries or schools.   The book is available as a free download from the AGF website <a href="http://agfgo.org/pages/bookoffers.php" target="_blank">here</a>, it is 86 mb, so expect it to take a little time.</p>
<p>The text in <em>Falling in Love with Baduk</em> appears side by side in Korean and English, following a style developed by Korean publisher Oromedia. Perhaps Oromedia had an uncredited role in developing this book. Oromedia’s <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?SpeedBadukForBeginners">Speed Baduk</a> series (9 volumes) has been all-English, but their other books feature side-by-side presentation of the same material in English and Korean. Examples include <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?KoreanStyleOfBaduk">Korean Style of Baduk</a>, the <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?ThinkLikeAProHaengma">Think Like a Pro</a> series ( 2 volumes), the <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?100TipsForAmateurPlayers">100 Tips for Amateur Players</a> series (3 volumes ), <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?InspirationOfPro">Inspiration of Pro</a> and <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?CreativeLifeAndDeath">Creative Life and Death</a> (2 volumes), all available from <a href="https://www.yutopian.com/yutop/cat?category=PAK">Yutopian</a>. Here, as in the other bilingual books, it’s fun to see what the authors have to say in both languages on the same page, especially for language learners. The English text uses Korean terminology for concepts lacking an English equivalent, rather than the terms of Japanese origin that Western players learned from the first generation of English go books. For instance, the position known as “atari” is called “dansoo.” The emergence of Korean-based synonyms may further bewilder newcomers who are already struggling to grasp the vast, abstract nature of the game itself. But in the end, it all adds to the ineffable richness of the game. The worldwide community of players has been unable to agree on a single set of rules. There is not even agreement on what the game should be called; we are unlikely to produce a universal lexicon any time soon. Confused readers can always consult Prof. Chi-hyung Nam’s <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?ContemporaryGoTerms">Contemporary Go Terms</a>, if they have one handy, but the question remains – if you want to tell your opponent that their stone is about to be captured, what should you say? -<em>Roy Laird</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/kba-donates-free-beginners-book-to-aga/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Six Days Left to Register for YKNOT3</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/six-days-left-to-register-for-yknot3/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/six-days-left-to-register-for-yknot3/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 01:05:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Roger Schrag</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Go News]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[U.S./North America]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=183875</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[The deadline to register for this year&#8217;s Young Kwon National Online Tournament has been extended until midnight on Wednesday, May 29. This means there are still six days to register for the tournament! Sponsored by Young Kwon of Pearl River,&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The deadline to register for this year&#8217;s <a href="http://www.usgo.org/yknot3">Young Kwon National Online Tournament</a> has been extended until midnight on Wednesday, May 29. This means there are still six days to register for the tournament! Sponsored by Young Kwon of Pearl River, NY, the tournament offers nearly $3,000 in total prizes! More than 60 players have already registered. <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/13Qiv1vIWeUp1WZIJi5Ew-Nek_TwRITbPRaQ5hKlMnAA/viewform">Click here</a> to register and <a href="http://www.usgo.org/yknot3">here</a> for details on schedule and rules. Join the wide range of strengths already represented and make this tournament better and even more exciting! The five-round tournament will take place June 1, 2, and 8 on KGS in the AGA Tournaments Room. For those who aren&#8217;t going to play in the tournament, be sure to check it out and watch a few games &#8211; a tournament with nearly 20 players 5D and stronger promises excitement!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/six-days-left-to-register-for-yknot3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>European Go Catalog Near Completion</title>
            <link>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/european-go-catalog-near-completion/</link>
            <comments>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/european-go-catalog-near-completion/#comments</comments>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 13:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Roger Schrag</dc:creator>
            <category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[Tools: books, software & hardware]]></category>

            <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.usgo.org/news/?p=183866</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Dutch go player Theo van Ees 1d, one of the authors of Bibliogo, is developing a catalog of go books and articles. The project started in 1975, and is now a listing of about 3,200 go titles in the main&#8230;]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-183867" title="" src="http://www.usgo.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/egcc-150x82.png" alt="" width="150" height="82" />Dutch go player Theo van Ees 1d, one of the authors of <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?Bibliogo">Bibliogo</a>, is developing a catalog of go books and articles. The project started in 1975, and is now a listing of about 3,200 go titles in the main European languages plus Russian. The European Go Cultural Centre, meanwhile, started a library of go books in 2003 and today this collection is managed by librarian Henk Mourik 1k. Database specialist Otto Versteeg 8k has put both collections together in a searchable database listing all of the titles in van Ees&#8217; catalog, with an indication of which items are available at the European Go Cultural Centre library in Amstelveen, Amsterdam. You can <a href="http://go-centre.nl/wordpress/european-go-library/catalogue/">search the go catalog</a>, and the plan is to update it frequently. You may report comments and wishes to van Ees at <a href="mailto:tvanees@xs4all.nl">tvanees@xs4all.nl</a>. He is especially interested to hear about omissions and newly published material.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/european-go-catalog-near-completion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
            <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>